Krish NAik: Yeah, hello, everyone, am I audible? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: I think the charts, that was just great.
Krish NAik: Yeah, just try to type in the charts, please.
Krish NAik: Well, red wine.
Krish NAik: Alright, so today we'll be talking about multimodal rag, and very specifically, the dock passing part.
Krish NAik: Okay, a lot of options are there, so…
Krish NAik: First of all, we'll be talking about the different paradigms that you guys can start working with and start exploring.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me start sharing my notes, okay, and then I will come to the main paper.
Krish NAik: The sign is a bit different, I think, a bit parallel.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, it is available.
Krish NAik: So, multimodal… simply,
Krish NAik: Right now, we'll be focusing on the vision part, okay? So, vision, very specifically.
Krish NAik: And why vision? Because if I'm talking about audio.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you have audio files, in the case of audio, what happens?
Krish NAik: you convert it into text, okay? So, you'll be applying something like STD-based modules are there, okay, or ASR…
Krish NAik: automatic speech recognition or speech-to-text, so these type of models, directly, it will be converted into text. And then the chunking strategies and everything is pretty much seen like a document. I won't say a lot of changes are there, but the toughest part, I can say, is the vision.
Krish NAik: Where actually you need to detect images.
Krish NAik: Okay? It can be charts.
Krish NAik: It can be graphs.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you need to maintain even the order of text.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I feel that the vision pipeline is much harder as compared to the audio-based pipeline. Similarly, like, if you have solved the problem of vision, then you can actually start working with videos also.
Krish NAik: In videos, what happens? You try to break the video frame by frame.
Krish NAik: So you can treat one frame image just like an image.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so frame by frame.
Krish NAik: So, the starting point is actually your vision part, where we'll be talking about the computer vision things a little bit today, because my main focus of today's class will be document passing.
Krish NAik: Somehow, you solve this particular problem, the rest of the part is actually a pieceke.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, simply, like, we will be focused on the document passing, and, like, there are two, important paradigms, like, they have their pros and cons, so we'll be starting with that. If you remember in the last class, we didn't, I shared a notebook, and you guys executed. Anybody remember that?
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know.
Krish NAik: the Kol Pali notebook.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: So, right now, I'll be talking about two different paradigms, okay? So, the paradigm… E?
Krish NAik: Okay, which is your, pool palli?
Krish NAik: And then we'll be going through the research paper also, Kulpali.
Krish NAik: And… The second is the Paradigm B.
Krish NAik: This is specimarch, pure computer vision task, like, layout detection.
Krish NAik: Plus?
Krish NAik: OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, so two things happens parallel, in paradigm B.
Krish NAik: pretty much in the output, I will say that you will be grading very similar results, but it actually depends upon scalability and other things that I'll be… So, first of all, let's explore the part with respect to pool palli first, okay? So, what happens in paradigm A, and exactly how a RAG pipeline is built?
Krish NAik: It is available in Notion. Google list, okay? Please have a check. I just, basically updated it, today.
Krish NAik: So, now let's focus on… the Kolbani-style approach.
Krish NAik: So, in this approach, what happens?
Krish NAik: For, let's take the example right now with a PDF-based document.
Krish NAik: Now, this PDF document… We'll be having multiple pages, so each page, you'll be converting it into images.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then you will be using some type of model
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, the model will be, like, Kulpali.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And using this model, you will be looking into patches.
Krish NAik: Patches of a document.
Krish NAik: How many of you know the meaning of a patch?
Krish NAik: In computer vision, we use the term patches a lot.
Krish NAik: or parts of parts of an image, okay? So, parts of an image, when I say that, it can be a part of text, it can be, one part can be something like a table, one part can be chart.
Krish NAik: Okay, it totally depends upon what are the different type of attributes you have in a single page. Okay, so those things that I'm referring as patch. Now, each patch will be converted into an embedding.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes, who will, do all these things? So, Pulpali will do both the things. So, first of all, the patch-finding part. In each, of the docs, sorry, actually, it's better not to write document rather than let me write image.
Krish NAik: Because patches are always available in images.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And then embedding, then your VDB,
Krish NAik: Vector database, and then rest of the things, pretty much the querial same things, that lies.
Krish NAik: Now, in this approach, what happens, really, like, I can say that
Krish NAik: You have lesser amount of control.
Krish NAik: the patch-finding part, is totally, with cold pali. It means that somehow if cold pali fails, okay, then I can say that there will be some type of problems.
Krish NAik: Now, when you actually move into these type of paradigms.
Krish NAik: Okay, the Cold Pelic-based, Coldplay was basically the first model, and slowly, slowly, like, every 3 to 4 months, there has been an upgrade, and the latest model in their family is the ColdPoint VL2.5. Okay, so the latest one is ColdPoint. I'll be sh…
Krish NAik: Telling you about this one.
Krish NAik: Cole Twain 2.5VL. So, this is right now the latest, model in the, family. Now, with Old Pali, they have brought a new benchmark also, okay, referred to as the Vidor
Krish NAik: benchmark.
Krish NAik: And this benchmark is very specific only to cold pali-based models only.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, now, as you have understood.
Krish NAik: the main part. So, now, things like Kulpali is based on what?
Krish NAik: Because, if you remember, something as cool birth.
Krish NAik: How many of you remember Colbert?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, please let me.
Krish NAik: Anybody remember Spohbart?
Krish NAik: That we have used for our multi-vector, multi-vector, guys, for multi-vector approach.
Krish NAik: Not sparse, not dense.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, you guys remember already. So now, cold pali is completely based on cool word. Okay, so where late interaction happens?
Krish NAik: Now, this late interaction part was even there in pool birth, okay? So that's why the pool palm, the main backbone, that happens, okay? So, it is based on… purely on pool birth, but the main problem is.
Krish NAik: It's a very heavy model. It's not a light model. It's not like that anywhere you can do the implementation. You always need a GPU. Without a GPU, it is not possible. Okay, so now, let's try to break into Kulpali the model architecture. What are the core components that you have in Kulpali?
Krish NAik: Then I will come to the late interaction part, a little bit much more in-depth.
Krish NAik: Okay, now… the paper. The main purpose of this paper is to replace the traditional pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, and what is the traditional pipeline? This is basically the paradigm B.
Krish NAik: Layout detection plus OCR, because layout detection, I can say that it's a very old research, like, from the past
Krish NAik: 6 to 7 years, like, a lot of research has been going around just for layout detection. Because I've… till now, I feel that, in production, if I'm going ahead with… I will not use full panel.
Krish NAik: But I will use Kolpal in certain, scenarios only. Okay, so that's why I'll be talking about those scenarios also.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, in cold value, what happens?
Krish NAik: Now, there is a vision importer.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a vision encoder is there.
Krish NAik: encoder model.
Krish NAik: And very specifically, it's based on Siglip.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Siglip is a model, there are many types of models, and now the purpose of this vision encoder is convert the image into patches.
Krish NAik: From… first, you will convert the PDF and… into image, and then the patches. What are patches?
Krish NAik: parts of the image. For example, there can be a chart, there can be a figure, okay, there can be a table.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from your main document.
Krish NAik: You can think about the parts of the document, which is basically your,
Krish NAik: Batch reference that we are calling.
Krish NAik: Now, once you have this… The first step
Krish NAik: then you will be having a VLM model, okay? So, for example, a VLM-based model.
Krish NAik: For here, you can use a simple LLM also.
Krish NAik: Okay, or SLMs can also be fixed. So, this is added benefit, it totally depends, like.
Krish NAik: VLMs actually… if you have VLMs, then you can actually do the verification. If you have only language models.
Krish NAik: then you cannot do the verification. Now, what is the benefit? Like, if I, ask you, like, okay, fine, SIGLIP, the vision importer, is converting image into patches, but if you want to really do the verification.
Krish NAik: I have not shared any links yet, I'm asking. It's okay? I'm just talking about the theoretical part.
Krish NAik: So, whenever you are doing any conversion, if it's a good practice, really, like, if you can do the visualization by yourself, okay, or the verification, because really, I don't know this model will give me the correct patches on.
Krish NAik: That is one of the things. It means that that part…
Krish NAik: You really don't have the control.
Krish NAik: Because I cannot say that, okay, focus on this one, this one. Now, I feel that I have lesser control.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, that's why, in the next step, you have this… any type of model that can be brought. In the original paper, they have actually used a language model, and they have not used a VLM-based. So, I think they have used something like Gemma.
Krish NAik: Okay. And then, finally, you have your embedding projection.
Krish NAik: From these patches, you'll be converting into embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the size of the embeddings are generally, like, 128 dimension till 768 dimension, that varies according to model, because there are many models in the family. So, like, I will start with 128 till 768, the rough number. Okay, that keeps on varying on this.
Krish NAik: Now, I will say that this…
Krish NAik: particular approach is really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now, when I say that, it's good, like,
Krish NAik: I feel that you have lesser control, but it really takes care of any type of visual things, rather than text. Now, if you have really a lot of text data in your document, then I will try to avoid cool pali, but if you have a lot of
Krish NAik: charts, lot of table, lot of infographics, lot of figures in your document. Then I can say that, really, I can go ahead. If you have lesser amount of text, and the main focus is much more on, attributes based on charts, figures, diagrams, okay, in that case, Kulpali, I feel that it's much better.
Krish NAik: Can't you give the, info to LLM? Okay, alright. Now somebody is asking, let's, go ahead, okay, to that… that paradigm is really costly. Just think about if you have a PDF, and you directly pass that PDF to a VLLM at every call.
Krish NAik: It's a very costly operation.
Krish NAik: That's a very, very, very costly operation.
Krish NAik: actually, like, not as scalable. It means that your… the cost of the infrastructure. If you think about it, let's take GPT-4O. I know that GPT-4O can do that, but really, like, the scalability and the control. If I pass something to an LLM, do you think that I have a lot of control.
Krish NAik: Because right now, for document parsing, I feel that I should have more control, too.
Krish NAik: So that's why I feel that always, that if you have a lot of images, figures, diagrams, in those cases, really, I can go ahead with Kolpali blindly. But if I have a lot amount of text, for example, academic papers I am talking about, I feel that, yes, Kolpali even works, but in some cases, I can say that
Krish NAik: It fails also.
Krish NAik: Whereas, if you have systems where you have layout detection with OCR-based systems, I feel that they are much better.
Krish NAik: So, in production, kolpali is used very, very, very, very less. The main problem… now, let's talk about, little bit about the problems that you face in Kolpali, because this is completely,
Krish NAik: a different way that they have gone. The main purpose of this paper was to replace OCR and layout detection completely. And they are telling that, okay, give me the image, I will do the embedding, and later on you can, actually query. So for rag-based systems, like, cold pali has been used
Krish NAik: I can say a lot, but again, not in production, in research, it's good. Now, let's talk about the cons. So, when I'm talking about the cons, the benefit is you don't need to handle anything.
Krish NAik: Just pass your document, convert into…
Krish NAik: Do you think that you have to do any type of conversions? Only the one thing is there, which is basically the image part. Once your document is available in images, for example, in a PDF, if you have, let's take 100 pages. Now, all those 100 pages will be converted into
Krish NAik: 100 images. Now, from those 100 images, multiple attributes will be extracted. And, so attributes, what I'm talking about, I'm referring them as patches form, okay? Now, let's take…
Krish NAik: the main cons that I…
Krish NAik: I feel in this paper, which is it. Now, generally, when you are doing indexing, it means that the final, embeddings that will be coming per patch.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, let's go with a number like 768 dimensions. Okay, now for each patch, when you have that.
Krish NAik: Like, in text, you have
Krish NAik: a piece of text, which is referred to as chunk, okay? And now.
Krish NAik: That chunk, you actually convert it into an embedding and save it in your vector DB. But here, the concept of chunking is totally gone.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it, guys.
Krish NAik: The concept of chunking is not their own.
Krish NAik: This is one of the major, I can say, differences, if you try to compare it with a text-based pipeline.
Krish NAik: You really do need to take care of jumping. Everything happens automatically.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, but here what happens, it totally depends upon this image and patch.
Krish NAik: Really, I don't know how many patches are there.
Krish NAik: Now, let's take one image.
Krish NAik: Okay, and generally, if I say that, the number of patches, because we don't know, this number will be dynamic.
Krish NAik: So, let's take 10 patches.
Krish NAik: But a beach.
Krish NAik: Page or image format?
Krish NAik: So, if you have… let's take…
Krish NAik: a document of 1,000 pages. So, directly, can I say that roughly around, because I cannot do the multiplication by 10, I hope you get it, guys, why I can't do it.
Krish NAik: Because this number, 10…
Krish NAik: is very dynamic, like, for every page, the number of attributes, the number of patches will be different. In some cases, it can be more than 10. In some cases, it can be less than 10. Is this part clear for everyone? If I take that rough number for now, because I need something, okay, so an approximate.
Krish NAik: So, directly, the number of vectors.
Krish NAik: that you have. I can say that it increased quite a lot, as compared to chunks, if I'm going at, let's take chunks. So, generally, in the text.
Krish NAik: Okay, it can be 4 chunks, 5 chunks, 6 chunks, 7 chunks, but really, like, 10, I have taken a small number, it can be even more, like 15 or so, 20, it totally depends upon the structure of the document.
Krish NAik: So, now, when the number of vectors are actually increasing, so what will happen?
Krish NAik: What will happen, guys? Tell me.
Krish NAik: Now, just think about… These vectors are increasing.
Krish NAik: First of all, your retrieval time will increase.
Krish NAik: And here, you really don't have a lot of control.
Krish NAik: It means that more, scalable system that you are building. So, let's take the example in future, if you have, like, 1 million documents.
Krish NAik: Now, for those 1 million documents, first of all, convert, like, in each of those documents, how many pages are there? Now, from those pages, how many patches are there? Now, there is no other way that it has to look into all the documents.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is one of the biggest problems. It means that if it's a small scale, I can say that to some level, you can, like, add metadata to
Krish NAik: I can say, to a certain level, like, in file-wise or through that, if there are certain matches, you can do that. But really, if your document is long, if I say, like, if you have a 1,000-page document.
Krish NAik: the reveal time.
Krish NAik: If it's a document as small, nothing to worry about, it can really handle
Krish NAik: Okay, so the retrieval time also increases. Now, this part, really, optimization, it means that if you try to convert, so generally, I've seen in some of the research, they try to perform quantization there.
Krish NAik: quantiation of vectors. Now, yes, for sure, this is a good approach.
Krish NAik: But always remember, with this approach, what is the downfall?
Krish NAik: with respect to your retrieval results. This will be done.
Krish NAik: This will also go down.
Krish NAik: Because if you try to convert a float 32 into intake.
Krish NAik: The retrieval speed will be better, but the drop with respect to the retrieval, that will go down.
Krish NAik: Page Intex solve this, page index also have some problems, really. Like, I'll be discussing about that later on. But, right now.
Krish NAik: This is the main problem. It means that the index storage that you have, or your vector TV storage, that will become massive with respect to time.
Krish NAik: And there, really, you don't have control. Whereas for text-based, retrieval systems, like, on top of those vectors, we can really apply a lot of quantization techniques, like scalar, product, binary, so many, optimizations, and they really work out great. But in the case of Cool Palum, really, it drops.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always remember the query time.
Krish NAik: compute. It increases. If your corpus is increasing with respect to time, and there is no other way.
Krish NAik: Okay, to handle it. Now, Cool Pali has been designed very specifically for English language.
Krish NAik: It means that multilingual support is not there.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that if somebody is building, again, he or she needs to do it very specific based on their language.
Krish NAik: Now, SK is asking, it has been, boosted with Gemini embedding recently, again, like, Gemini embedding, yes.
Krish NAik: It's not like Gemini, Google Gemini has done a very late launch SD. It's not like they have done something straight-of-the-art. They are pretty much one year behind. There are multiple models that came last year. The same thing which Gemini does.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, like, I don't feel it. Yes, the multimodal support, they have really dropped this thing, and and I think in your main application, I have kept it also. Gemini 2 embedding, if you really want to use our OpenAI embedding. Okay, so don't worry about it.
Krish NAik: Now, when you are actually working, so I will say that poor poly systems are not scalable. Now, you need GP.
Krish NAik: This is the other con. It means that in a CPU, you cannot do an inference. It might take
Krish NAik: 3 minutes, 5 minutes, 3, the inference time is very high. In CPU, not possible. You always need a GPU.
Krish NAik: This is the other problem.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, whenever the, cool palli systems, you have, so GPU, it means that, just think about whenever you need to,
Krish NAik: make a query, you have to be sure that, yes, like, my… I need a GPU. Without a GPU, it is not possible. So, it means that the compute infrastructure is really high.
Krish NAik: always, this requirement will be there. You cannot use it with a GPU. So, even in the last class, if you remember the practical, I told you do it in collab. Same thing cannot be replicated. The model size is only, like, 8GB, okay, which sits on top of VRAM, so then only it becomes faster.
Krish NAik: Now, the VLM backbone.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, when you really think about, processing your document, okay, document processing, it means that
Krish NAik: if I say about my document processing time.
Krish NAik: I upload a PDF, that PDF gets converted into images. Now, from those images, patches, patches to embeddings.
Krish NAik: This process really takes time. It's not, like, super fast. Neither you can optimize it.
Krish NAik: So, this document processing time is also…
Krish NAik: This is also high. It means that in some cases, if you really think about, okay.
Krish NAik: If you're running it in the background is some GPU, because for everything, you need a GPU, and really, on GPU also, it's slow. So, think about, in CPU, it is not possible, it might take a lot of time just to do the indexing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, these are a few of the main problems.
Krish NAik: So, that's why I feel that, Pulpali is good, but again, with respect to scalability, you should always ask this question. Should we go ahead or not?
Krish NAik: So that's why most of the multimodal rack-based systems, they work on paradigm B.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: But this is one interesting paradigm, and that's why I'll be looking into the paper also, so that you guys know that, because I feel that there are, even under paradigm B that I have, even I can actually divide it into two different paradigms.
Krish NAik: I think when I will come to be, then I will discuss. But for now, if I say…
Krish NAik: So, pull panel, text-to-imit patches, and they're simply embedding. So, really, you do need to take care of chunking and other stuff. It's really good, but again, I feel that
Krish NAik: Competition is a very expensive task, so research is good, but really, if you want to bring it to production, your infrastructure cost will really go up. So, I feel that, if you go with layout detection-based OCR-based systems, they will be much cheaper as compared to this, because at the end of the day, both the things can be built out.
Krish NAik: With Kolopali as well, we can extract the image from the document and then pass it.
Krish NAik: Actually, it will be patches.
Krish NAik: We share. So, it is not about an image.
Krish NAik: Gold Pali takes the input as an image.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: And for image cropping, if you really ask me about, like, if you talk about cropping up images, but that really, I don't feel that you should use Gold Pali, if that is your goal, Abhishey.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that in that case, layout detection models are much better, much more lightweight, which can be executed in lighter environments.
Krish NAik: Only image. Yes, only image, not full document will be converted. If you, in your document, if you have 10 pages, those 10 pages will be converted into 10 images, and from those 10 images, it will come. Is there any benefit? The mean benefit? Less,
Krish NAik: I can say, you really, like,
Krish NAik: you don't need to work on chunking and other things. It's pretty much direct. That's why I feel that it is good in some cases, if you feel that the number of documents won't be scalable. But one important factor.
Krish NAik: If you really feel that, in future, your documents will be highly based on infographics, charts, tables. In that case, Pulpali is good, actually. Like, you feel that, yes, in our case, I will be having always less amount of text in your documents.
Krish NAik: So, what type of document you have, based on that, take the decision. Because I know people use Kulpali in production, but in those cases only, where, really, the amount of text is very, very… okay, and it's pretty much image, charts, okay, so the attributes are pretty much visual-based attributes, rather than text-based attributes that you have.
Krish NAik: Now, Chaitan is asking if the PDF contains text 75% plus, can't we use typical data parsers?
Krish NAik: And yes, you can use that.
Krish NAik: If I have 75% tax, for sure, I'm going to be going with Kolbani Perso.
Krish NAik: With Pulpali, you really do need to take care of charity, okay? Now, that's the normal, the paradigm B that I'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Doesn't fit for engineering, yes, you can use for CAD-based tasks.
Krish NAik: Because for, civil engineering-based plans that you have, in those cases, I've seen people are using Pulpali.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: PowerPoint presentations, I will go ahead with Kulpali, but again, like, if you have a lot of visuals in your PPT.
Krish NAik: In those cases, it's really good.
Krish NAik: Rather than working. So, but if I'm working with academic-based papers, for example, like research papers from archives, okay, in that case, again, Pulpali, I wouldn't prefer so much.
Krish NAik: Sometime in scientists, we have spectrum kind of images, then yes, now see.
Krish NAik: Now the question comes, with those spectra-based images, how much text information that you have, it also matters. Like,
Krish NAik: I feel that if you have that information, it means that, the image is there, and below the image, there is some type of, okay, Figure 1, and then you have a short description that actually helps you.
Krish NAik: Now, don't think about if you ask something which is totally out of the context. In that case, I think Nawabi was asking the question, so it don't. If you have some type of image, description, really, it's good. Without description, it becomes hard.
Krish NAik: If my data set is screenshot from video, then Pulpali is good. Yes, in that case, Pulpali is really good on it.
Krish NAik: If you have purely visual data, see, the main focus on Gulpali.
Krish NAik: Was if you're really working with visual data, then this is one of the best approaches.
Krish NAik: Because, this is pretty much like visual computing, rather than, I will say, simple text-based computing. So you need more infrastructure costs. That is one of the major pain points that we have.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's look into even the paper, and what in the paper that they are trying to say. I think you will get a better prospect, like, the main purpose of the paper.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think this is…
Krish NAik: Because when first time, Kurpali came, I feel that it's really, really good.
Krish NAik: So, like, this is the hugging Face.
Krish NAik: I think link, and this is the archive link, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is the main guy, behind the manual, I said. Okay, so generally I track his Uber, so he continuously updates most of the things in their repo.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the package is, full body engine.
Krish NAik: Gold Pali Engine Data Hub.
Krish NAik: So, this is the main work that I do track.
Krish NAik: So generally…
Krish NAik: Exactly, like, the things which are available. So, as I told you, there are a lot of models. You can see the pole pali.
Krish NAik: They have a very specific benchmarking system, which is the Veduri benchmark, so they're in the Veduri benchmark. If I look into the results, yes, the first version of Pulpalis, then multiple updates, has been provided, 1.1, 1.2, 1.3.
Krish NAik: I think the latest one is, 22.5, V0.2.
Krish NAik: Tomorrow AIO has also brought their another model based on, Coral Pali, which is based on the Quen family, the Quen 3VL.
Krish NAik: So now I will be, going to the, that, page, first of all, the research paper, and then we'll be coming to… because those are small, small model objects that they have brought.
Krish NAik: Now, if you look into…
Krish NAik: Majorly, so 8 years. Okay, so very much the European research groups, they have worked on Goldpal. Efficient document retrieval with visual language models. Visual language models, why?
Krish NAik: Because the first step is SIGLIP. SIGLIP is a vision importer, and later on, you can bring VLL into the systems.
Krish NAik: Please share the link in the chat, alright, just wait.
Krish NAik: If you have missed two classes, I think in the last two classes, Saturday, there was no class, only on Sunday, I have not discussed anything important to me.
Krish NAik: Alright, so documents are visually rich structures that convey information through text, but also figures, page layouts, tables, or even fonts.
Krish NAik: Since modern retrieval systems mainly rely on textual information they extract from document pages to index documents, often through lengthy and brittle process, that struggle to exploit key visual cues efficiently. And this is really, like, if you are working with any type of parsers.
Krish NAik: Regularly, they always focus much more on text, rather than on image.
Krish NAik: And it's pretty much a truth.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are actually working on visual-based document parsing, then the models will be visual-based. Text-based models can not really handle those type of things.
Krish NAik: This limits their capabilities in many practical.
Krish NAik: document retrieval applications such as RAC.
Krish NAik: To benchmark current systems on visually rich document retrieval, we introduced Vidu, which is a visual document retrieval benchmark, composed of various page-level retrieval tasks, like spanning multiple domains, languages, and practical settings.
Krish NAik: The inherent complexity and the performance shortcomings of modern systems motivate a new concept, doing document retrieval by directly embedding the images of the document pages.
Krish NAik: Okay, so directly embedding, so you have to think about that, it means two attached things are there, but this is the abstract part in the paper, so they are directly pulled. So here they're talking about, we released Kolbani, a visual language model trained to produce high-quality multi-vector embeddings. Why multi-vector? Because I told you, Kolbani is based on cold birth.
Krish NAik: Okay, the same concept, because CoolBot is very specifically text-to-text. Kulpala is image-to-text.
Krish NAik: have, okay, from images of document pages, combined with a late interaction matching mechanism, so most of the times in the late interaction, they might use a mean pooling, but that they have changed with late interaction, I can say, in the core architecture level.
Krish NAik: Pulpali largely outperformed modern document-retrable systems while being drastically simpler, faster, and end-to-end trainable.
Krish NAik: We release models data codes, so this is basically their, homepage. If I try to open this one, you will see that, yes, this is the main one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and they have already multiple models, and if you really look into the benchmarks, so let me just…
Krish NAik: Focus here.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the benchmark comparison of different type of models. If you really look here, so NDGC is basically the retrieval methods.
Krish NAik: In a RAD-based system. So, in NDGC, I can see that the NVIDIA family has launched something, the Nemo, 1 billion and 3 billion models, they are working good, the Genome V4, okay, call NUMIC models, so the call.2.5, so, so many models are there.
Krish NAik: And from here, really, I can say that, yes, it works.
Krish NAik: Okay, so based on the benchmark, when I look into anything above 0.5, I will say that it is good. In the field of visual computing, if you get such results, I will really say that it's good. I won't say that decent. It's really, really good when I look into this particular benchmark comparison.
Krish NAik: What is the meaning of late interaction? So, late interaction happens means once the documents are loaded, then actually the token breaking system that happens, too. Okay, so that's… Ravi, others are not info, informing about voice break. Okay, so have a check from inside.
Krish NAik: All right, now, with respect to the models, so this is, the same thing in the research paper, the same diagram is there. Okay, I'll be talking about the diagram, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Okay, now coming to the collections. So, let's look into the different type of model collections that they have. Now, they have, built multiple models based on domains also, like finance, industry, pharmaceuticals.
Krish NAik: And I feel that it's really good, because they have built their own data sets, and on top of that, they have trained, and they have open-sourced the models. So, at any point of time, if you want to do domain-specific tasks, you can directly pick up their, models. So, where you have a good starting point.
Krish NAik: Now, every year they update the benchmarking system also, like Benchmark V1, V2, so the benchmark is also not a static one. Every year, it gets updated.
Krish NAik: Now, this is domain-specific benchmarks. Now, this is a part where I'm much more focused on right now, because as we are talking about Kolally, so these are the main Kulpali models that you have.
Krish NAik: You can see, I cannot say a very recent update that has come, but this approach is a bit older. So, if you look into, these are pretty much 2025-based models.
Krish NAik: None of them are 2026.
Krish NAik: Okay, every model that they have launched, and right now, this is November 25, this is the latest one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then comes the 12 family, so…
Krish NAik: Initially, they started with the Gemma family, okay? Now, the whole Pali paper is based on Polygem, okay? The PaliGemma model is from Google, but later on, they switched to the Quen Family, because Quen family has actually brought a lot of things like MLHA, okay, very similar to DeepSync, okay? GT UA Beast is also there, so with respect to…
Krish NAik: based mechanisms, I feel that. Quinn, the Chinese, models family, they always test it out in different ways, okay, and somehow. So, simply, they change the family also from the Google family to the Quinn family. And this is where I feel that
Krish NAik: Again, if you look into 2025 updates, but these models are much better as compared to the, original pool polyacons.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, there you do have even published a few of the OCR-based models. Okay, so this is the OCR-based, again, which is widely used, I can say, for RAC-based applications.
Krish NAik: Page OCR, video OCR, some paper resources that they have pro- even the data set that they have used, everything that they have open sourced.
Krish NAik: Now, let's get back into the paper. I think. Let's open the paper once more.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, in the introduction part.
Krish NAik: I told you the main idea was to replace OCR and layout-based models. So that's the same thing that they have written in the introduction.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you really look into Uber, recent years, pre-trained language models have enabled large improvements in text stem building models. In practice industrial settings, however, the primary performance bottleneck for efficient document-reactable streams
Krish NAik: Not from embedding model performance, but from the Prad data ingestion pipeline, for sure. Really, the quality of embedding doesn't matter if you have not done properly the data parsing.
Krish NAik: Data parsing is the toughest part in the rag, that I feel, based on your documents. You really need to work much more on parsing.
Krish NAik: So, here they're talking about indexing a standard PDF document involves several steps. First, the PDF parsers of the optical OCR systems are used to extract words from the images. Then comes the document layout detection models.
Krish NAik: Can then, be run to segment paragraphs, titles, and other pages, such as tables, figure, headers.
Krish NAik: A chunking strategy is then refined… is defined, to group text passages into some semantic poems and a modern reiterable setup. Now, this is the setup even that we'll be working in our project.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this setup that has been mentioned, everyone, please do focus. Okay, now this setup. I'm not for sure they are comparing, because their idea is to completely replace this type of systems.
Krish NAik: Now, can you see here, they are focusing on two main things. One is the OCR, and the other one is the layout detection, or the document layout detection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… DLD-based tasks and VCR-based tasks. Now the question comes in paradigm data we'll be exploring. You have a lot of options to play with.
Krish NAik: there are more than 20 to 30 different options. Every cloud provider, they'll have their own OCR. So, I can say that it's better, it's cheaper, so everybody should go in this particular direction much more. But in this paper, the main purpose was to replace these type of systems.
Krish NAik: And I can say in some cases, yes, the results that they got back in 2024, it really impressed, as compared to the over-year performance of the systems back in that day.
Krish NAik: In our experiments, we typically find that optimizing the ingestion pipeline yields much better performance on visually rich document retrieval than optimizing the text embedding model.
Krish NAik: All right? Now, this is the main image that you have to look into, what they have done here.
Krish NAik: So, this is a document. Now, this document
Krish NAik: On top of that, OCR, and then layout detection. Now, see, this combination can be before and after. I feel that, first, you should not do OCR, first you should do layout detection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it totally depends upon, like, both the things can be… one thing can be first, the other thing can be first. In research, I have seen the paper, so first OCR and then layout detection, as mentioned in this paper. And from this paper, you can see that chunking has been done.
Krish NAik: From that chunking, again, it has been passed to a text model, and then finally comes your vector-tech-based operations, okay? And from there, you apply your similarity score-based algorithm, okay, and you get your results.
Krish NAik: Now, here what they have done, simply, like, they have taken, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, see, this 0.39 second is, again, based on GPU. Okay, so that's why I feel that, they have not told about in GPU, it is not possible to do it in 0.39 second per page, but they have written it here.
Krish NAik: Because on CPU, this inference time is much higher.
Krish NAik: Now, here, they are taking that main image, I can say. That image has been broken into multiple patches, so that's why they have brought that particular line. Then they are passing it through SIGLIP, which is basically the vision encoder. From the vision encoder, we'll be getting the patches. Those patches will be,
Krish NAik: sent, for embedding-based projections, then your LLM comes, and finally, a maximum similarity score operation that happens. Now, this part, the similarity score operation, is pretty much the same, because I can say that,
Krish NAik: When you do this simulator-based task, it means that your embedding-based projections of the patches of the image are actually being saved in the vector table.
Krish NAik: So here, in Figure 1, they are telling that Cool Palace simplifies the document interval with respect to standard pipeline methods, while achieving stronger performance with better latencies. The latencies and the results are mentioned in Section 5 and subsection B4. We'll be coming to that.
Krish NAik: Okay? No, this is the main task, which is the retrieval in visual space concept.
Krish NAik: And this is the actual focus, because I can say that in 2024,
Krish NAik: nobody actually started working on, like, vision page document passing a lot, and this was the first game-changing paper, so that's why everybody talks about Kolbani.
Krish NAik: After projection, after projection, it will save. Projection-based embeddings means the embeddings are ready, and it will be saved to VectorT.
Krish NAik: And, in this case, I think the LLM that they have used, it's GEMAT2, I think. Gemma 2 billion model that they have used in this paper, for this particular LLM.
Krish NAik: And later on, this has been upgraded to 10VL models, which is much better as compared.
Krish NAik: The retrieval time has increased in… see, the retrieval time will increase some, but if you have a lot of vectors.
Krish NAik: If you have lesser amount of vectors, then the retrieval time will be lesser.
Krish NAik: I told you, if you try to make your system much more scalable.
Krish NAik: Okay? In that case, if you have more and more vectors, because here, that level of optimization actually cannot be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, I hope you get it, because here you have that limitation. You really need to look into all the vectors for your document that you have. So somehow, if you have applied some type of filtering mechanism, that, okay, now this particular question.
Krish NAik: Okay, and somehow you have figured that, okay.
Krish NAik: I can do some type of filtration, and I can reduce
Krish NAik: that looking into lesser number of vectors as compared to looking into the vector team. Now, that optimization, in some cases they have done, it's worked, but in some cases, it really didn't work.
Krish NAik: All right, now, what is the rule of the LLM FK is asking? The main rule of the LLM is contextualization through cell potential.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: without an LLM, I can say lesser, because one is only the encoding part.
Krish NAik: After the encoding, you need to add contextualization. That's why that, LLM has been used.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Now, these are problem-based settings that they have used in this paper. R1, like, strong, retrieval-based performance, high throughput, corpus, and taxation. Okay, now, these are… they have talked about a lot of rack-based, systems. In those rack-based systems, how the textual retrieval methods are used.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Mikish is asking, what is projections? Projections are generic, what is used in the field of neural networks?
Krish NAik: Because when you try to convert a patch of the image.
Krish NAik: into a multidimensional space. But that particular task is referred to as a projection.
Krish NAik: Very similarly in the Transformers papers also, you have multiple projections for your query metrics, for your key metrics, for your value metrics, okay?
Krish NAik: There you are. That, projection is pretty much the same.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, here they're talking about neural-based retrievers. Yes, we do use one of the simplest examples we have looked into, the, rack paper. When we looked into, like,
Krish NAik: DSP-based systems, intense passage retrieval systems. Those are one type of neural retrievals. Then comes your multi-vector retrieval, where, late interaction, this is the cool part part. In the late interaction, paradigm introduced by CoolBird, an embedding is pre-computed and indexed per document total.
Krish NAik: So here, it will be pretty much document token. It will be per document patch.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the idea is to benefit from rich interaction between individual query and document terms while taking advantage of the offline computation and faster query. Offline computation, really like offline computation, the model that you'll be using of Cool, but it is pretty much of high size.
Krish NAik: Okay, because it has been trained on a dataset where you have that, question-answer pairs, based on, multi-patch
Krish NAik: Of different type of documents.
Krish NAik: SK is asking, can there be any index created for patches? Any index created for… it's not about any index. You have to understand, every image, or basically every page of the document will be different.
Krish NAik: And for every patch, There will be an embedding which will be generated.
Krish NAik: Because the concept of quick retrieval, if you have lesser number of documents, I can say quick retrieval.
Krish NAik: But, if you try to make it much more, like, 10,000 documents, then the renderable type of whole file actually goes down.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Pages will have correct multiple patches and the embedding created, but if there is an index created… Index is fine. Index, you were talking about the vector DB right now. In a single index, you can keep all those things.
Krish NAik: you can add filters like page 1, page 2, so that during your final retrieval, you will have the source truth also. For example, this particular diagram belongs to this page, and this is the diagram number also. In that way, we can keep the metadata, which helps us.
Krish NAik: Okay, and actually, like, it becomes faster, correct?
Krish NAik: The main problem is we have to look into the entire index.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that, because that is… because that part in between, if you try to
Krish NAik: figure it out, that, somehow we need to look into lesser number of factors. Now, that optimization is not being standardized in the entire KnPAi ecosystem.
Krish NAik: Everybody is applying their own. So, not a single rule of thumb that I guess.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, contrastive vision language models that they have used, which is basically the SIGLIB,
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that case of, Cool, but also the contrastive learning happens. I told you about contrastive-based learning, which are basically discriminative-based models.
Krish NAik: All right, now, Polygema. So, you can see that the PolygeMa 3 billion model extends the concepts of Pali 3. Okay, for the projections, or basically for the encoding part, they have used SEGLIP,
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are the core ones, and later on, this polygema has been changed with Quinn PL models.
Krish NAik: Now, benchmark design based on different type of academic-based tasks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so language, queries, documents, descriptions that they have provided. Okay, now this is the widower benchmark that they have designed only for their, tasks. So, whenever a new model is, I can say, released from the pool.
Krish NAik: Pali family. In 2026, there hasn't been a single one, but, every time they focus on this particular benchmark. And I feel that the implementation of Cool Pali has really been implemented by NVIDIA research also.
Krish NAik: So I can say that, yes, in…
Krish NAik: Nvidia research, a few models are there, which are actually using Cold Poly, but again, like, actually using it in production, I feel that the infrastructure cost will be very, very high.
Krish NAik: Now, here, DocWikiWeb, which is a visual question answering data set. So, when you look into VQA, always remember, these are visual question answering data sets.
Krish NAik: Okay, infographics, that is there, research-based is there. Okay, then, table formula with, quarter-based. Okay, now this is for a table-based system. Now, they have taken multiple academic-based tasks.
Krish NAik: and some, industry-specific, like the energy sector, government, healthcare, AI, okay, and they have done it. But again, I feel that in these, domain-specific tasks, the data set that they have used is much smaller.
Krish NAik: Okay, so current access systems, so when they were publishing the paper, unstructured was it. I think everybody remembers the framework unstructured, we have discussed dock lengths.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now they were comparing it with unstructured.
Krish NAik: So, I felt that back at that point, like, back in 2024, really, like, unstructured for visual document parsing, it was not really great, I can say, though they were using certain models, but again, the output
Krish NAik: it was not so much good as compared to, like, right now in the work with Unstructured.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: unstructured with some type of image captioning-based model. So, image captioning, you will see that a lot of time, captioning has been used. Now, whenever you are working with unstructured, if you remember, even if you are working with DocLink, now, these type of systems, when they are working with visual document parsing, they always work with OCR.
Krish NAik: How many of you remember that? With Dockley, you have Rapid OCR, EasyOCR, Tesseract, very similarly with Unstructured, also, they have Tesseract.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Do you guys remember? Because for visual document passing, that has been the strategy. It means that you need to integrate some type of OCR-based systems. But really, layout detection-based systems have not been integrated back that time.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that OCR is fine, but actually, I need to work much more on my layout detection.
Krish NAik: Because layout detection, and you see, like, when you have, like, multi-column, okay, and in that column, if you have images, you need to really maintain the order of text.
Krish NAik: order of that images. So, really, those things plays a very, very crucial role.
Krish NAik: Now, they are talking about OCR-based things with captioning. Now, what happens, like, if you have
Krish NAik: some type of system through which you can detect layouts. Now, if you can really understand that if this is a table, if this is a figure, or some type of chart, then actually you can crop that, and you can keep it in a folder, and later on you can apply a VLM on top of that.
Krish NAik: which will actually help you to perform an image captioning-based task, so you can get a much more detailed caption. Okay, now that particular text, you can actually save it in the vector DB, which can give you a better result.
Krish NAik: Dockling detect layout? Yes, correct. In Dockling, there are multiple models, because after
Krish NAik: this, because right now I'm discussing paradigm A, then I will come to paradigm B. Don't worry. Okay, Anilo?
Krish NAik: Then, comes your embedding modules, so they are talking about, we embed textual chunks, we evaluate the OCAPI VM25, so generally, the main traitor of the algorithm is referred, like, OCAPI is the main…
Krish NAik: I can't say the actual… because BM25, we call it, but it's actually Okavi BM25.
Krish NAik: And with that, they have taken the Coolboard-based implementation, so that's why BGM3 is also mentioned here, if you look into that. VGM3-based system.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, contrastive VLMs that they have talked about, so here they have used Seglip, but the other options are GINA CLIP also.
Krish NAik: Okay, clip-based models. Clip, is also totally open source, that model can also be used, but they are used yesterday.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, the latency that they have pulled. PTF-based parsers, Layout detection, OCR, captioning.
Krish NAik: Okay, really, it takes a time. I can say that, yes, these things will take a time. Why? First of all, layout detection.
Krish NAik: Then OCR, then captioning. It means that from this layout, whatever the thing that you got, that will be passing to a VLL.
Krish NAik: They will do the caption for you.
Krish NAik: Okay, and whereas with respect to SEGLIP and COLPALI, it's pretty much direct image-based encoding that they are generating for patches. So, for sure, this will be a faster process, but again, they are not told about where they are talking.
Krish NAik: Because I feel the working of the PDF passers doesn't matter whether you are working on a CPU-based system or a GPU-based system. If it's taking 7 seconds, it's fine. But ColdPalia and SIGLIP, not possible on CPU-based systems. So that part there really have not focused on.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a late interaction, if you look into. Okay, so for the visual language models and the late interaction is pretty much like pool, but I can say.
Krish NAik: not, mean difference, because the implementation in the mean pool bot, with respect to multivector, it was 128, but I feel that, going ahead with higher dimensions, like 512 is much better for patches.
Krish NAik: Then, the late interaction part, given the query, Q for document D, we denote, so this is, the main formula for LI, which has been represented, because here, multi-vector. So, when I say multi-vector, what will be the dimension of that multi-vector?
Krish NAik: So, when we were working with Splate, can anybody remember what was the dimension for Splate?
Krish NAik: Kolpali is a paradigm based on SIGLIP. Kolpali is a paradigm based on vision encoder, Jagapati.
Krish NAik: Don't tell that sickleipun.
Krish NAik: It can be any type of vision and border.
Krish NAik: They can use CLIP also. The main purpose is vision encoding, and later on bringing an LLM for contextualization.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's… okay, split, yes, 30,000. So, similarly, whenever you are working with, like, multi-vector systems.
Krish NAik: they also bring a certain dimension, to that, I can say, but it will be lesser. For sure, it won't be, like, 30,000.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the main perspective of multi-vector representation in the common embedding space, okay, where N and QD are respective the number of vectors in the query, and in the document page embeddings, because
Krish NAik: Here, the embeddings that are happening. Like, you can actually keep this information in your metadata, okay? Now, this particular patch will link to this particular image, so in that way, you can do a page-based indexing operation. Now, these things I'll be showing you later on, when I'll be showing you a full-scale-based system.
Krish NAik: The late interaction, Eli that, that, they have referred here, okay? Now, this ELI, operation is the sum overall, okay, of the query vectors, of its maximum dot product, so that's why the maximum operation. Now, this max SIM is basically the maximum similarity.
Krish NAik: Where you apply it with respect to query in every dimension.
Krish NAik: Okay, of the embedding vector, so based on that. Now, I will say this, late interaction is good in some cases, but not in every case. Because in Pool Pali, without late interaction, their main, I can say, the fundamental, implementation has been based on PoolBut. So that's why, without late interaction, none of their model works, actually.
Krish NAik: And I feel that, this particular implementation is good, but again, in production, going ahead with late interaction-based systems, the retrieval becomes a bit higher.
Krish NAik: The latency of the retrieval.
Krish NAik: And, really, like, if you're working with GPU, then it's a totally different thing, but, every time working with GPU is not a solution. This entire thing,
Krish NAik: I feel that somehow it can… if it can be optimized, then we can actually move it into production.
Krish NAik: Much more. Because right now, I feel that it's pretty much in the POC state for majorly most of the organizations, because continuously working with GPU-based systems, it becomes much harder.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, contrastive lasts, okay, finally they are talking about what are the different data sets, some tests with, like, Cloud 3s on it.
Krish NAik: And are those visual-based systems that they have worked with.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is a comprehensive evaluation of baseline models, based on their, Vidore benchmark.
Krish NAik: Okay, so unstructured with BM25 and VGM3, which is purely based on cold water, so…
Krish NAik: archive-based documents that they have not really published it, but I feel that
Krish NAik: the purpose of not publishing, it means that it really doesn't work. That's why it's pretty much blank, because BM25 and BGM3, they work only on text-based systems, and right now, in…
Krish NAik: archive, for sure, you'll be having a lot of infographics. It can be tables, diagrams, and other things. Once they have introduced OCR of the unstructured, they somehow got 31
Krish NAik: Now, if I look into the NDGC results, so these are all NDGC-based benchmarks, and somehow it processed more than 50 to 60, I will say that it's really decent.
Krish NAik: Right now, the OCR backend at that particular point of time was pretty much daily OCR.
Krish NAik: Now, unstructured with captioning, Now, in this particular case, what happens? So, let's take…
Krish NAik: Now, see, this particular option is a very costly option. It means that
Krish NAik: For every image that you will be getting within your documenting, we'll perform a captioning-based operation. For that, again, you need a VL.
Krish NAik: Okay, or if you have an image captioning model, but again.
Krish NAik: robustness of the model will be towards the lower side. So, I feel that captioning-based models is better to send it to a VLM-based model, like GPT-4, or you can use Opus, those models are much better. When VL
Krish NAik: So, somehow, you can see that the retrieval metric increased from 31 to 40.
Krish NAik: For this one, because captioning gives you much more detail. In captions, you have the control. You want to generate small captions, detailed captions, okay, because that is pretty much text generation, based on the, visual. I can say…
Krish NAik: Patch of the image.
Krish NAik: Then, they have tested with multiple, vision encoders, like JinnaClip, Nomic Visual, Seglip, because in their case, the vanillas, the Seglip worked really good, so that's why, in their paper, the main implementation has been there with Seglip only.
Krish NAik: And then finally, they are bringing their main,
Krish NAik: full-based implementation, the Kulpali with late interaction, and really, like, this is 79.1. So this is a very, very huge change. That's why, like, Kulpali is referred as, like, one of the main game-changing papers.
Krish NAik: And, if you look into document VQA, here, this is the lowest one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, plus plus, it means, like, from the previous implementation, how much better it is. Like, in the field of, like, visual computing, anything it surpasses 5-10%, we see that it's a pretty much game-changing paper, but here they have actually done much
Krish NAik: bigger changes. Okay, the amount of benchmark data has increased, it's really, really high.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why this was all about the paper, and I feel that this is really a good one, okay? And everybody, like, I think Together AI has also fine-tuned their own version of Pulpali.
Krish NAik: And, they use it on your own platform. You can get an API, and you can do the testing. Leveraging multi-vector embeddings through in late interactions of Pool Pali, those things.
Krish NAik: Offline indexing, online querying. So, a few things that have been mentioned here.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Okay, so measures, can you see? NVIDIA L4 GPU. Everything has been done on a GPU, not on a CPU, guys.
Krish NAik: L4 GPO, how much VRAP you have in an L4?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me, you should… guys should know at least NL4.
Krish NAik: Yes, and then L4, how much VRAM is there?
Krish NAik: Raja is saying 64, no, it's only 24GB of RAM.
Krish NAik: Generally, we start with T4, then we move to L4.
Krish NAik: We finished selling, got only 10%, like,
Krish NAik: You have to really, like, later on go through the paper, you will be getting a lot of important things.
Krish NAik: Because this is one of the points, because this paradigm is a bit different with… Okay.
Krish NAik: you have to actually understand, because, see, here, a lot of things are there from computer vision perspective. If you really are not familiar with computer vision, a lot of things, like, own with so much feel, and even with respect to transformers.
Krish NAik: Like, based on vision-based encoders, like, how it is different from normal by encoders, those type of…
Krish NAik: Things you need to have a clarity on those.
Krish NAik: Then it becomes much easier.
Krish NAik: for you to understand, okay? So… All right.
Krish NAik: So, I feel that, in interviews, sometimes the questions are being asked from Bulpali.
Krish NAik: But again, like, very, very, like, less production.
Krish NAik: very less people actually move it into production. That's the main pain point of this, particular people. It's really good, but it comes with a cost.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the first one. Later on, just go through the paper, because I feel that in the field of RAG, with respect to visual document passing, this is the first big leap that has been there.
Krish NAik: What model do you suggest? What model regarding what? Which model means which one?
Krish NAik: Are you talking about the… from the family of Kolipaleovic model?
Krish NAik: If you are working in 2026, go with the, Colecoin VL, 0.2.
Krish NAik: What model do you use a Google Pali versus there are no other frameworks?
Krish NAik: Kulpali has upgrade agents, but really, there is no such a direct competitor of Kulpali, because then you have to move to paradigm B. That is a totally different paradigm.
Krish NAik: So, really, like, the family of the Pulpali, really, they don't have competitors. Like, very similar, based operations, nobody has done it. So, in research, they are pretty much unique on this one.
Krish NAik: So, always remember, you can actually go to the main GitHub, and you can look into the Fedore benchmark. From there, look into the NDGC. So, here, if I say that 90.6, so this model… I can say that this is a much better one. For their VLLM, they have used 23VL.
Krish NAik: The vector dimensions, they have changed, like, to 320 dimensions, okay? So, in that way, you have to look into, like, every, model is…
Krish NAik: unique to some major changes. It's not like that they are not using, but multi-vector embeddings will be there, because that's the fundamental of Coolboard.
Krish NAik: This is more of a rag-based approach, exactly.
Krish NAik: How about direct inferencing? Direct inferencing is a costly operation. Abhishek, nobody does it.
Krish NAik: If you pass a PDL, and let's take a VL element, GPT-4,
Krish NAik: That becomes… because your token consumption, if the number of token consumption by increases, it becomes huge. I hope, Abhishek, you get that.
Krish NAik: Because GPT-40 will take the charge, and it will price you per token. So that's why direct inferencing, though it's a solution, but I feel that it should not be done, because it is not scalable.
Krish NAik: All right, now this one… okay, so that's why now I think we can go back to our, this one, the main implementation that we have done last time. Okay, so again, we will just go through the notebook, because as I have told you, a lot of things are there, so let's quickly…
Krish NAik: executives.
Krish NAik: I think in the last class, I have already done it. Do you guys want to do the execution?
Krish NAik: Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, what should be used? I will come to paradigmA. I've just discussed a very small part of multimodal rack, because in multimodal rack, the main thing is here, nothing you need to worry.
Krish NAik: directly pass, and rest, everything it takes care of, but it comes with a cost.
Krish NAik: Are you ready? Are you ready to pay for that?
Krish NAik: Okay, I think already I have a T4 attached with me, and this is the same notebook. Again, I'm sharing the link in the chat. If in the last class nobody has done the execution, we will do the execution.
Krish NAik: Which part you wanted me to explain, Satish?
Krish NAik: I will come to paradigm B. That is much used, much more efficient.
Krish NAik: Satish, please let me know, like, which part.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Alright, fine, we will go through.
Krish NAik: Because it's pretty much self-explanatory. So, first of all, I have shared the notebook, okay, so let's install. I think these 3 packages are required, optimum, but…
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, bits and bytes are required. Okay, so let me do the installation of these three packages.
Krish NAik: Actually, I don't feel I need anything, because this is collapsed, so transformers come pre-installed, and please don't execute any other cells, so let me just delete this.
Krish NAik: It's much, better in that case.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this is just a check, I keep these type of cells if I'm executing sometimes outside collab, okay, or sometimes even collab also, it is helpful, so it actually tells me, but you really don't need to run this cell also.
Krish NAik: What you need, actually, only, like, these three packages, the QuenVL utils, bits and Bytes, and Optimum.
Krish NAik: Because, we need Accelerate also, Transformers and Accelerate, but both the packages come pre-installed in Transformers.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: You can do the same thing in Lightning, if you're doing it in Lightning.
Krish NAik: In the last class, I showed it in Lightning Raja, so I'm not going to show you, because Lightning comes with that. If you do it in Lightning, you'll be exhausting some credits.
Krish NAik: We did in the last class before, stop the module in the space. Yes, exactly. So Ham, if you want, you can switch on that, but I feel that this is an easier practical, guys, so do it in collab, don't spend your credits. You have limited 15…
Krish NAik: credits only in Lightning, so why spend on that? Later on, I know that.
Krish NAik: It will be better from some other use cases.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, coming to, Bialdi. Now, this is also a wrapper on top of Kolpali, then you have the Kolpali engine, Pillow, which is a vision library, Python.en, even Googlegeni, because right now I'm working with
Krish NAik: the VLLM. I'll be getting it from, Google.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simply please do the installation of this.
Krish NAik: Cold Palai Engine is our actual package.
Krish NAik: Okay, the main wrapper, which is handled by manual phase.
Krish NAik: That is a mean guy, always remember.
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm telling you. Because generally, I track his work.
Krish NAik: Okay, you get very less updates, but I feel that It's good, actually.
Krish NAik: diluting tech.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this… So…
Krish NAik: And, okay, one part, you guys later on, if you want to explore, they have a very specific notable sections, like, I'm not going to discuss all the notebooks, but if you want, you can actually look into this.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I feel that if you really want to test it out, like, they have integrations, like, Viviate have a dedicated, blog, because Kulpal is pretty much FEMA, so every, I can say, VectorDB organizations, they have created.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can see here, like, Daniel is there, Merv is there, Manu is there. Okay, so these guys have created, actually, a lot of tutorial based on Pool Pali, but always remember, you need a GPU. Without a GPU, nothing you can do.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, simply, like, if you want to test this, a few of the notebooks might be deprecated, you need to work on those package-level things, but really, it's a good place. Last year, I've checked all the… but now I have not checked so much, okay? So this part, please explore by yourself, because so many notebooks
Krish NAik: the fundamental thing is same. If you actually worked on this one, the vision rack tutorial, that is…
Krish NAik: I can say it's a good one.
Krish NAik: Other than that, you really don't need to check every other book.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think the installation of done is with respect to the packages, I think. Now, load.env, so I think, I don't have any, things, because actually I was executing this, I think, in a lightning environment, because of that, load underscore.env was there.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm using the model cold prevent2V1.0.
Krish NAik: Now, this model, I can say that this is pretty much an upgraded version.
Krish NAik: Here, your actual LLM has also been changed. You are not using any more polygema, rather than you were using PenVL.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from BiolD, so there is a direct class through which you can actually load a multi-modal rack, so this particular class is there, so I'll be directly loading the model, and when I load the model, simply just look into the size. The size is really, like, high.
Krish NAik: Now, 8GB. 8GB is actually… it means that you need a continuous VRAM.
Krish NAik: furthest. Without that, it is not possible only.
Krish NAik: Here we have to ex… you don't need to explicit, I have hard-coded it later on, you do anything.
Krish NAik: For me, that doesn't matter so much. I will just get a, a Gemini key for now.
Krish NAik: University.
Krish NAik: Because I think in the last class, I've already…
Krish NAik: deleted, or something like that, but an API key.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is taking some time, because this is not in my control. Out of 8GB, only 4GB has downloaded.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the main thing, like, why it's not used in production.
Krish NAik: Okay, see guys, I think I have my key here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, you can see 8.5 GB.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me get a random document one.
Krish NAik: Because this is the attention is all you need paper.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, based on, Linux, it has a dependency of popular utils.
Krish NAik: Okay, since the Cool Pali GitHub repo, it has been mentioned, so we have done the installation of Poplar.
Krish NAik: Now we are creating an index.
Krish NAik: And we are not using any vector DBs, because that is not my priority. It's a simple index that we are right now saving.
Krish NAik: Which comes from BioLT, and in vector, implementation, because later on, I can switch to any vector TV.
Krish NAik: Now, this part will also take time.
Krish NAik: Because, I feel that, this is T4, T4 is very much slow.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, if you move to a better GPU, at least, like, L4, L40S,
Krish NAik: Those are much better, because the indexing speeds is low.
Krish NAik: For every page, it's actually doing that.
Krish NAik: I have a single document, so the document 0 is the actual in-text for the intern.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I can say the indexing has been done. We are good to go for a query.
Krish NAik: Chaitany's asking, we use embedding models.
Krish NAik: Yes, here there is no spare embedding model.
Krish NAik: Kolpali does the embedding for you.
Krish NAik: We are… okay, in this case, we are reading, but Kulpali, behind the scenes, it will do those things. No, this is the part where it has actually converted the PDF into image, image into patches, patches, into embedding-based productions, then passing it to the LLM for contextualization, and then finally saving it.
Krish NAik: Cheta. It's pretty much direct, you don't know, but it's happening.
Krish NAik: As the model has been defined, okay? Now, what is the blue score for a transformer-based model? Now, this is a question which we have taken from a table, rather than from a direct text.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let me just, do… so you can actually look into the results variable, but, the actual image data, so see, results 0.b64,
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Now, let me just do a conversion so that actually you can look into the image.
Krish NAik: Okay, so some information with respect to Bruce Course, I feel that, which is there right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, now let me pass my key.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Gemini 2.5 Flash, I'm not using any Gemini 3 recent models, I think it should work.
Krish NAik: So, now this particular answer, if I actually show you from where it has brought attention…
Krish NAik: all you need. Okay, so at least open the paper for your own reference.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this question is from tables. Like, this will be my main document for the docklink report going forward.
Krish NAik: So, yes, this is my main one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a cushion, actually, which has been taken from a tape.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is where, if you try to go ahead with normal text embedding.
Krish NAik: With your normal checking waste approach.
Krish NAik: most of the parsers, if you go with PyMu, PDF, and others, they fail. On top of tables directly, don't work. So, for the base model, okay, 27.3 and 38.1. Okay, and I can say that here's the results here.
Krish NAik: 27.3 and 38.1, the blue score for the transformer-based models. So I can see that, yes, exactly, like, it can actually fetch the information.
Krish NAik: Okay, now…
Krish NAik: I have not really worked on VectorDB and other stuff, because I feel that it's good, and later on you can attach your own VectorDB, and you can do those things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please,
Krish NAik: get, because now, I feel that this is really good, because when you actually try to fetch the information, because this is rag.search, you're simply searching right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in that embedding space, you are actually saving the base 64 also, if you remember. Here I have store collection with index. Now, here, if you make it true, actually.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you are saving the base64. I hope everybody knows the base64 representation of an image. So if you have that particular, like, for every page, because this is actually the entire page.
Krish NAik: And that image to base64. I know that Base64 is a pretty much long string, but later on it actually helps you to do the inferencing.
Krish NAik: So in that way, you can actually do the verification. I know that, yes, I'm getting the result correctly from the correct source.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear for everyone? Please let me know, then, because we'll be exploring much more things, the paradigm D now, I will start after this.
Krish NAik: Murthazra is asking, please explain again which part.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if you want, you can save the complete, so, PDF, PDF to image, and then patches. That PDF page, you can actually save it.
Krish NAik: into a base64. Later on, if you want to use that Base64 to render it.
Krish NAik: the size of the vector TB index, for sure it will be bigger, because the size of base64 strings are very, very long. But if you want to really do that, you can do that.
Krish NAik: That's why. It means that you can save your base64 representation of the original image.
Krish NAik: That's how Bilet has configured their main multimodal rack class. So you have the option to save the original base64, because this is actually the original image.
Krish NAik: So you are saving that image in an index.
Krish NAik: Later on during your retrieval, you are using your base 64.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's like saving the original chunk in the metadata, exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Because, see, this variable, if you try to get it, let's look into this, just results.
Krish NAik: In the results, what do you have? C.
Krish NAik: Whenever I'm not printing anything, you guys don't get it, just try to print that variable at least.
Krish NAik: Here, it's telling the doc ID, I have a single doc only right now, 0. Page number of that document in 8. Score, 18.85, which is the maximum score. Right now, no metadata very specifically, and this is the particular base 64 of that page.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody get it.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, others. If you have questions, simply ask me.
Krish NAik: Because, then I will change the complete paradigm only.
Krish NAik: Everyone, please let me know.
Krish NAik: It is… it is a page or patch, no, this is a page, page, page. Base64 is the page, page, page. No patch.
Krish NAik: Chaitan, this could be… can this be done through typical Python reader utilities?
Krish NAik: Yes, you can convert it into… you have no. I think you don't need to install basic C4 package, it comes default with Python.
Krish NAik: If you install Python, you can use the importBase64. That package is a pre-built one.
Krish NAik: Cheap.
Krish NAik: Now, here, BioD does it for you.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, you can use a Python utility.
Krish NAik: works even well for complex images yet. It, works. Kolpali really works. No issues. API key is required, just pass an API key, no, this is free, that's why I've attached Gemini, you guys don't need to pay.
Krish NAik: Little salt, but I assume it's because of G2 capacity. Just have a check.
Krish NAik: Because, the compute credits, you can see you currently have zero, even I don't know, like, when. Poor hour, 30 minutes, so I have also lesser compute.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so I will just… Disconnect and delete the runtime form.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: So, I will say that, test it out with other PDFs. In your case. Everybody, please take 5 to 10 minutes, do the testing.
Krish NAik: Because the next paradigm that I'll be discussing is a totally different paradigm. This approach is not there. That is pretty much your classic RAG-based pipeline approach. So please do have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please upload a different PDF, test it out.
Krish NAik: How many have you done the practical?
Krish NAik: I have added attention, you can pass any research paper also here, because in the code, you have that
Krish NAik: You just need to change the length.
Krish NAik: Yes, so please do test it out, some other research papers.
Krish NAik: If you have any questions, ask me.
Krish NAik: Because, really, like, I don't suggest anyone to use cold value in production.
Krish NAik: Okay. The only time I will say that, if you have
Krish NAik: Lot of images in your document. Only image, image, image. In that case, it really helps.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do the testing with some other PDFs, and then let me know, because after 10 minutes, then we will discuss the paradigm B.
Krish NAik: Yes, I've given 10 minutes to do the testing.
Krish NAik: Then we'll continue with Dockling Ranite.
Krish NAik: Okay, you guys do the testing, and then let me know that whether it's working
Krish NAik: Per your document, anything complex that you want to pass.
Krish NAik: Nagash is asking, so basically, Kolpali returns the relevant PDF page.
Krish NAik: For a query, okay, a relevant PDF page for a return, the relevant… no, no, actually, if you are saving that information, then…
Krish NAik: Gateway.
Krish NAik: The information will be extracted from the embeddings.
Krish NAik: Of multiple patches.
Krish NAik: Not from the entire PDF page, Najesh.
Krish NAik: SK completely out of the… as if, we are faced with the challenge, the user and the customer upload the file.
Krish NAik: Okay, and we, our automated person, have to sort the document and pick the upload, if it has a lot of text.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can use a hybrid-based system in that case.
Krish NAik: If you have a certain, like, decision-based routing SK, I can say that.
Krish NAik: And actually, you can do that using a…
Krish NAik: Now, that thing I will tell you, okay, if you want to use that routing-based logic, that logic can be decided from the help of ParadigmD.
Krish NAik: Really, we don't know, like, who are doing that.
Krish NAik: Because if there are any apps also, nobody will tell that we are doing.
Krish NAik: If you calculate.
Krish NAik: the hybrid, logic actually needs to figure out how many images are there, tables are there. Once you have that, then you can take the decision, pass it to open.
Krish NAik: Actually, yeah, it will be like a hybrid, hybrid system. If you use hybrid search, dense.
Krish NAik: plus sparse, plus your copil, and that's it.
Krish NAik: I am… I'm… see, I have, not seen any implementations directly if they're doing.
Krish NAik: If you ask me implementations, but I've seen production, but behind the scenes, what they are using, really, nobody has no idea.
Krish NAik: If somebody's using also, they will not say that we are using pulled bulk, or something like that.
Krish NAik: Chetan is asking, the model used in this practice cannot be run. In local, you can do it.
Krish NAik: But again, few… See, in local, if you have VRAM, then only I will suggest.
Krish NAik: If you don't have VRAM, then the execution time will be very, very high.
Krish NAik: The document indexing part, if you remember, this one, okay, because first of all, loading the model into the memory, there you might get an error. You can try it in your local, this same notebook that I have shared, if you want to do it in your local.
Krish NAik: Because at least I know in Apple Max, you have a unified memory. If you're working, if you have at least, like, 32 gigs.
Krish NAik: a param, then at least you can try it out.
Krish NAik: This process will take a very, very long time, Jayka.
Krish NAik: This one.
Krish NAik: In our project, I want to be using Pool Pali, really. Like, I feel that for Pool Pali, I, need
Krish NAik: Much more compute info.
Krish NAik: I can keep it as a separate one, as an optional one, but again, like, I feel that… because, see, my first choice is not cool by.
Krish NAik: my choice is always the paradigm. I feel that it's much cheaper if you're actually making scalable systems.
Krish NAik: If your system is not scalable, if you feel that, okay, fine.
Krish NAik: very large documents. If you have a limit, then only I can see that.
Krish NAik: But, again, like, the retrieval speeds will go down as you start skipping. That's one of the major problems with Kulpan.
Krish NAik: In Lightning. In Lightning, the infrastructure is somehow better as compared to Cooler.
Krish NAik: So you guys do the testing and then let me know that, is it working for complex documents? Like, a few people have told me yes in the chat, similarly you do. I feel that the results are really good.
Krish NAik: For a few things, like, there was one client
Krish NAik: For whom I was having, like, XRA reports. In that case, I suggested him for balloon.
Krish NAik: So, it depends upon use case, it's not, like, every time.
Krish NAik: Can I say Azure Document Intelligence, Chaitan, you were talking about? Yes, it's a very similar thing, because there they have already different type of pre-trained models, similarly in Google Vision, similarly in AWS, they have already the APIs. The same thing, but yes, you don't know what this API is.
Krish NAik: The main purpose is to at least understand a little bit of the engineering check.
Krish NAik: to build this type of systems. Otherwise, directly consuming an API, that's not a solution.
Krish NAik: That's the main purpose. Little bit you know about that, and later on you can explore much more.
Krish NAik: In an interview, skulpali is a common interview question.
Krish NAik: Everybody will ask.
Krish NAik: Because the results are actually really good research. But the main problem comes when you actually scale.
Krish NAik: If you have very good GPUs, like A100s, actually, like H100s you are using continuously, I can say that you can
Krish NAik: you can actually use Coolpan.
Krish NAik: But that infrastructure cost is the mean.
Krish NAik: VLMs perform better contextualization as compared to LLMs, in the case of images and others.
Krish NAik: Generally, if in your resume, you have written… in MVPs, I have seen that people mention Kulpadi.
Krish NAik: It's not, it's not regarding resume, it's very specific to visual document parsing.
Krish NAik: Document passing is a very common question. Now, in those cases, if somebody asks you about visual document passing, then you have to talk about this paradigm, which is the AO.
Krish NAik: Okay? Like, coal polybase systems, exactly how they work. In that case, you need to explain.
Krish NAik: In my system, it doesn't work, Smitesh.
Krish NAik: In my local, it doesn't work.
Krish NAik: I've not tested with a 40GB or a 48GB. In my local, it's only 32GB, but you can do the testing, and you can let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if somebody has, like, 64GB of RAM, try cold polyEl, later on they can.
Krish NAik: Abhishek, we can do,
Krish NAik: Abhishek is asking, yeah, you mentioned with VLMs, we can do verification. Here's, like, the verification of the patches.
Krish NAik: Very specifically, if you pass it to GP24 in that case.
Krish NAik: Like, whether the table is a table, whether the equation is an equation, whether the chart is a chart for that.
Krish NAik: That's a separate API call, not within your Kolipali engineer machine.
Krish NAik: Apart from the cost implication, what will be the difference between cold pali and directly accessing multimodal? See, directly, if you're accessing the token cost, most dazza, it's just think about you are passing a PDF, that PDF will contain how many tokens? Just… I am worried about that cost only. Other than that, GPT-4 and others, everybody has that particular support.
Krish NAik: multimodal systems, you can directly use them. There is no problem. You can use GPT-4O and others.
Krish NAik: But I feel that why you need to send the entire document for one question?
Krish NAik: See, if you are working with GPT-4.0, then now the question comes, okay, alright, now you'll be looking into that, okay? You have to create a prompt, in that prompt, you have to mention, okay, look for chart, look for equations, and everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, in that way, you can create, and you can return, some type of a result which you can actually save it in the embedding. But I feel that passing the entire document to a VLLM is not a good approach.
Krish NAik: Because, it's very costly.
Krish NAik: With time… like, if you just compare the cost of using GPT-5 Nano and using GPT-4, you will understand that cost is only… but the same thing can be done.
Krish NAik: Without the cost implication, yes, it is completely possible. The same thing, Kolvali, I feel that
Krish NAik: They've really… if you think about the cost part, and later on the retrieval part, if those are the cons, if you are ready to go ahead, yes, you can use full palli.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking less than a minute for 26 pages.
Krish NAik: On a T4S GPU, it is fast, but the retrieval is slow, okay?
Krish NAik: Abhishek is asking, Pulpali will require GPU, which will be more than GPT-40? Your question, I did not get it, Abhishek.
Krish NAik: You first of all ask about a GPU, and then suddenly you have moved to GPT-4 pool. That's why I could not get it.
Krish NAik: Okay, which will be much costlier, GPT-4U.
Krish NAik: Just take an example, Abhishek. One hour, a T4 is charging you $0.9.
Krish NAik: Para.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in that 1 hour, just try to pass.
Krish NAik: like, let's take the example you are passing 100 PDFs.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: For 100 PDFs, how many tokens you will have? Based on that, tokens, do the accounting.
Krish NAik: For 1 million tokens, if somebody is charging $2, $3, I hope you get it, Abhishe.
Krish NAik: Ulpali really works great. Like, really, like, I'm really impressed the first time I tested back in 2024, even I was…
Krish NAik: like, but that's… few cons are there. Generally, for my… when I work with much more visual computing guys, I prefer working with Kolbani, really, like.
Krish NAik: people working in computer vision, where they are working with X-rays, interstellar-based systems, okay, even for certain genome structures, I can say. In those cases, with respect to good documentation, good quality images.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I can say that.
Krish NAik: the results of Pulpali is really impressive.
Krish NAik: And this is actually the, right now, the model that you are using is ColeQuen VL. That's much better than Kolban.
Krish NAik: Because, I think with respect to the NDGC metrics, at least, 15% better benefits.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think now we will move to the next paradigm.
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Should I proceed?
Krish NAik: Alright, let's talk about our next paradigm.
Krish NAik: I think this is, like, better release.
Krish NAik: We will continue, because I feel that I've given, for your own testing time, Rajat, 10 minutes to everyone.
Krish NAik: What is this paradigm? This paradigm, I will come. Don't worry. This is a paradigm which the, guys were trying to replace, the Kulpali guys, the detection, and the layout part, okay? So that will be our paradigm B.
Krish NAik: So, when I'm talking with respect to, both the paradigms, I feel that my… yes, like, the benefits with these type of systems are really good, because now I will come to your classic RAC-based systems.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, your paradigm B consists of two important things.
Krish NAik: Okay? In some academic papers, they do OCR first, then layout detection, but I feel that we should do layout detection first. Okay, so that's my personal choice, so based on that only, I will be telling you the paradigm.
Krish NAik: With respect to pros and cons, I feel that you should always understand the structure of a document. Once the structure is defined, then you should go for an OCR-based operation. In that way, the chunking strategy can be better.
Krish NAik: So, layout detection, first of all, you try to understand what is the layout of a document. Like, a multi-column document, for example, with respect to research papers that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, for this, you have one model, Model A.
Krish NAik: And then you have… Model B.
Krish NAik: Two different models. Always remember this one, the thing that I am telling right now. Okay, so layout detection plus OCR, two different types of models are used.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: Let's focus a little bit on layout detection, then I'm coming… then I will come to OCR part. Okay, now, when I say that, okay, for layout detection, what are the different type of models? Are there?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys?
Krish NAik: With respect to layout detections.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the part, the layout analysis part. I can say the first major research that I failed, it came from Microsoft. Layout, the paper was Layout LM. Okay, so I think I read that paper back in 2022 or 2021.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that was the first one. So, but after that, a lot of things that came. So, here, I will just mention one part layout for now. Because you have two separate models.
Krish NAik: Okay, so two separate models I'm starting with, because this is a, see, paradigm B
Krish NAik: Can be defined into, again, two separate, one is a… two-stage pipeline?
Krish NAik: Okay? And then you have a one-stage pipeline.
Krish NAik: In paradigm B. It means that if there is a model which can do both the task, layout detection and OCR, as well, parallel, if there is a model, good, you can use that, I have no issues. One of the simplest examples is they would run parse.
Krish NAik: It does it for you.
Krish NAik: Okay? And most of the systems, if I say that, they use two different models.
Krish NAik: So that's why two different models that you need to actually load it on your GPU. So I will say that, yes. Now, I will start with something state-of-the-art, and then I will come to a little bit down and down. What are the other options? So right now, this is 2026.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, I think this is the March month. So, I think in January 29th, PP, layout, okay?
Krish NAik: Okay, this PEP, dock layout.
Krish NAik: This one came.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is from Paddle.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think everybody knows about Padel OCR.
Krish NAik: Padel OCR, paddle OCR, guys.
Krish NAik: Pada, Lucia.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, Chinese, for sure.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these guys, and the letters, and this is from Baidu, always remember this.
Krish NAik: Baidu research is also really good, so I'm just telling you from where you have. Because from Paddle Paddle, you have this PPDocLayout. This is a very specific model, only for layout analysts.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, the second one is based on YOLO. YOLO is an object detection algorithm which is used, and from the Open Data Lab, there is a dock layout YOLO model. This is an older one.
Krish NAik: Okay, in our project, I will be incorporating ppdoc layout. Okay, the refund one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in our project that we'll be doing, so in that case, I have taken this one.
Krish NAik: Now, doc layout note, these are all the models that you guys need to explore by yourself. It means that, see, here, the options are, like, 50-50 models. I'll be showing you a few demos for sure, don't worry, I'll be taking up a unified bit, like a single stage, and then I will be coming to two-stage systems also.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, drop layout is there, then layout LM from Microsoft.
Krish NAik: Layout LM. It has multiple versions, V1, V2, okay? So, I feel that the V3 is the latest one, which is based on, DIT. Okay, and I will say that it's good, based on the results, based on transformers.
Krish NAik: Then, in India, there is a Surya layout.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is also good. In the benchmarking, I have seen the results are really good on OMI benchmark. Okay, so you have here the OMI benchmark.
Krish NAik: Omni.
Krish NAik: O-M-N-I, sorry.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally.
Krish NAik: Omni benchmark. Okay, so based on this benchmark, we actually evaluate our, OCR-based systems. Okay, or whether for your layout analysis also, that you can do it. Then, in the case of Dockling, Dockling has Heron.
Krish NAik: All the things that I am telling, they do the same thing.
Krish NAik: Dockling has heron-based models, okay, which you can actually use.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, right now, I think 5 examples I have given, it's more than enough, but there are more and more models. Now, this is the part where you can actually work with. NVIDIA has a very specific, layout analysis model, which is available. You can use that also, it's called as, like, Nemo layout.
Krish NAik: analysis, and that, okay? Then, once you have solved the problem of layout detection, then coming to OCRs.
Krish NAik: Okay, the next part is, first do that, then we will come to OCR-based systems.
Krish NAik: I think the last week, the technical report came from GLM, so I will start with GLM OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, this is a recent one. I think in our project, I've incorporated the latest one. Otherwise, this place, you can bring your
Krish NAik: anything, like, any cloud APIs also, you can actually do it. Like, I feel that most of the systems, like, you can work with Mestralos here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: OCR-based systems. So, really, this part, you always need to do the research, and you need to come up, like, what are the latest things that are happening.
Krish NAik: Any other OCRs? Recently, Quentin came, that is also good. Then you have Paddle OCR.
Krish NAik: That is also good, I will say.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can work with, like, easy OCRs, GLM OCRs. Now, the other one is Minor. Minor is also good, because I feel that this is one of the most widely used
Krish NAik: systems of the world. This is from Shanghai Labs, Shanghai AI Labs, and the Open Data Lab. Collaboration Minor Review is also good. In our practicals, minor view is there, so don't worry.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I prefer Minorio, because if you look into the GitHub, the number of stars are more than 50K, so I really feel that it's good.
Krish NAik: Then, with DOT OCR came, I think, from the red team, last week. That is also a good one. DOTOCR. This is from the red team. Then, Surya OCR is also there.
Krish NAik: These are all state-of-the-art, all these OCRs that I'm referring, guys.
Krish NAik: These are all open source, you can do your own implementation, that's all.
Krish NAik: Now, with these OCRs, very specifically, if you want to do some type of table recognition.
Krish NAik: Okay, because you have to really understand for tables, they have very specific models, like Dockling uses table format.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Padel OCR uses the Padel OCR VL. They have a very specific model, like a table recognition. There, they have a prompt which adds that the… convert that table into an HTML format.
Krish NAik: Okay. Then, another one I forgot is Monkey O's here. That is also good.
Krish NAik: Okay? Monkey OCR.
Krish NAik: This is also, I've tested. Then, from NVIDIA family, I forgot, you have, Nemo, OCR.
Krish NAik: So many OCRs are there, guys, really. Like, I feel that for the past 1 year, there has been a saturation with respect to improvements in the entire OCR system.
Krish NAik: All the paper comes.
Krish NAik: somebody can be good in finding a table, somebody can be good in finding an image, somebody can be good at finding an equation, but really, the saturation in the research of OCR for the past one year, I feel that there has been a pretty much
Krish NAik: saturation. I have not seen major improvements for the past 1 year, because in the last 7 days or 10 days, more than 5 busiers that have been, launched, new papers and reports that came.
Krish NAik: all these OCRs, everything is open source, guys. Whatever the thing that I have written here.
Krish NAik: The entire stack, all these OCRs that I have written. I'm not telling about, like, Google Vision API, like, Microsoft Dock Intelligence, neither AWS system. Those are pretty much closed source. I don't know what happens behind those things. But, when I'm talking about this paradigm of me, I'll be focusing much on… more on open source stuff.
Krish NAik: Relative?
Krish NAik: Mr. Lucia is only the Enterprise one I think I have written here. Sorry. Because, see, this is Enterprise.
Krish NAik: Okay, we will be testing, that also. Don't worry about that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I feel that, I have told… okay, now you need to use this combination. It means that you know this combination, okay, and you know this combination. Now you have to create a, you know the models from there, now you have to create a combo. Now, creating the combo is totally up to you.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, for example, you will tell that, okay, Paul, so…
Krish NAik: let's pick one, recent one. So, in our project that I have added, for our OCR is GLM OCR,
Krish NAik: Okay, and with, paddle-pedal wheel.
Krish NAik: Okay, so paradel, VL, dock layout.
Krish NAik: This is one combo that you can use.
Krish NAik: Plus…
Krish NAik: GLM OCR, or you can use, paddle OCR also, there is no restriction. Then you have to really create this combo according to you. There is no such thing as a general rule of thumb.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the PPDocLayout, okay, it's… rather than writing this one, let me just remove this one and write me here, ppdoc layout weekly.
Krish NAik: This is the latest one, I will show you, even in the Hugging Face, I think it came around January 29, one of the latest ones, so… but…
Krish NAik: And GLM, this is, I think, the last week the report came, so I was actually looking into the implementations, and it hasn't
Krish NAik: API, as well as an OLAMA support. So, I feel that you guys really don't need to work on GPUs. With an OLAMA support, it will take time for sure in your local machine, but at least executable, so we don't really need to worry about…
Krish NAik: Now, when I say this PP layout with GLM-based OTS, now from here, like, you can create your own, like, let's take, again, PP. Now, I feel that, right now, the best layout model is, PPDocLayout. So, I will try to create the combos with this one, possibly.
Krish NAik: Then, with this, I will… can work with Paddle OCR. You have to create your own combos, then you have to do the research, because this part is pretty much much more practical.
Krish NAik: Okay? Then, if you are working with minor leak.
Krish NAik: MinorU has its everything own. MinerU has its own, like, the dock layout, which is based on YOLO. See, MinerU uses the Yolo dock layout.
Krish NAik: And the results are really good, I will show you that part also, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Because I'm really a fan of MinerU. Okay. And with that, MinerU has a VLM also.
Krish NAik: Okay, it has its own VLM, which is, I think, close to 2 billion parameter. Okay, so that combination also works. So, it has…
Krish NAik: a simple OCR-based, like, sometimes you can think about OCR, like, text recognition, they have it inbuilt, in, the minor, so when you do the implementation of Miner, automatically all the models will be downloaded in one shot.
Krish NAik: Then, in, Dockling, if you're working with…
Krish NAik: Dockling, models, users to the Heron system that they have. Okay, like, they have a model which is the Heron 101, and that is really good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Head on?
Krish NAik: 101, this model is actually used.
Krish NAik: Okay, with that, for the OCR-based system, okay, they use that, granite. Okay, so that, really, like, a single model can do it, or break it into two different models. So, I will show you the response of a 256 or that 258MB model is bad.
Krish NAik: the OCS doesn't work, but if you switch it into a better model with a billion parameter, the results are good. So, practically, also, I will show you that. So, herald model plus…
Krish NAik: layout with that 258MB model.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, these are a few of the things. They're similarly, like, leave Monkey OCR, and others for now, because this combination needs to be decided by.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a combo that you separate. It means two things you pick up, and you create your own combo. Now, as I told you, now, these are called as two-stage.
Krish NAik: Take care!
Krish NAik: So, simple, dual stage, these are patterns.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, there are some unified models also, which is single stage, okay? Now, I will come to single stage.
Krish NAik: Single stage, or called as unified models.
Krish NAik: One of the best examples is Nemotron Brass.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, this is another one. I feel that it's good, but sometimes it fails.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, because when I tell you something.
Krish NAik: Practically, also, I will try to show you, like, sometimes where it reads in some cases. In a little bit, the documents are much more complex, in those cases, it fails, but really, I feel that this is also a good one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, you really now need to work on, like, what are the others, like, single-stage systems that you want to work with, or dual-stage?
Krish NAik: Okay, and everything here is based on GPU, nothing that can be done on a CPU.
Krish NAik: That is the most important thing. If something is there, try to look for more models which are having OLAMA support, then actually you can run it in your local.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now, we will come to the part with respect to testing. So, in paradigm B, try to divide it into two things. The single stage and the dual stage. Okay?
Krish NAik: In the single stage, it means that there is a single model which can do the layout detection plus the OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you have dual stage, where you first do layout detection, a separate model for that, and then you have your, text recognition.
Krish NAik: Okay? So remember, in paradigm, we also, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Now, you have to really look for what type of data, so I generally decide in, dual-stage system, for example, GLM OCR. GLM OCR is really good if you have, I can say, a text.
Krish NAik: Okay, more and more amount of text is there, I feel that in that case, GLM OCR really works good. With few images also, I can say that. I'm not written till now the deep OCR family, but you can… guys can hope you understood about that.
Krish NAik: So… but, this part is really good. Now, APIs are available similarly, if you directly think about if you want to work with Lama Parse. Llama Parse will do the same thing in one shot. Make an API call, or a single stage closed, like GPT-4, if you ask me. That is a single stage.
Krish NAik: It can do both the things. Mistral OCR, I've taken one example here, but remember, Mistral OCR can also do both of the things. Gemini, 3 Pro or 2.5 Pro, that is also a single stage. It can do both the things.
Krish NAik: But it comes with a cost, that's the main problem. AWS Textract, it also can do both the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, always remember, when you are trying to divide into this paradigm, in this paradigm, there is a single stage and the dual stage. So, break your main, like, your implementations. Keep it in such a way so that you can always do the research and the experiment.
Krish NAik: More than a single stage means both the layout and the detection OCRs can be done in an AS. A single model will do it.
Krish NAik: Later on, because today I'll be exploring much more open source models, but later on, I will give you a task so that at least you guys can try it out with Gemini 3. Pro, okay, or GPT-4. Try to design a prompt, and based on that, try to fetch the results.
Krish NAik: All right, now,
Krish NAik: Majorly, I think that, this part, we have worked. Now, a little bit, let's, get back to our practical implementation, because exactly what we are going to do and whether the results are good or bad.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'll be sharing the notebook once I have done the execution.
Krish NAik: Because this aggregation event, I'm not sure that it will work or not.
Krish NAik: Yes, so I think this is,
Krish NAik: Dockling Granite one, okay? And now, for Docklink granite, you have a model. As you can see, I will go to this IBM granite, okay? And there are a lot of models. Can you see HHH?
Krish NAik: Hmicro, H, these are all Heron.
Krish NAik: the family of Heron that I was talking about. If you look into here, HHH, Head on.
Krish NAik: With respect to Docklink, they have this one, 258MB, and this is the MLX, which is for Apple-based systems.
Krish NAik: Like, if you want, really, you can try it out. Apple guys, okay, it works, but again, a bit slow.
Krish NAik: They have very specific embedding models also. Now, these are all visual things, whichever I'm showing you right now.
Krish NAik: The entire Granite family consists of, visual, computing models.
Krish NAik: All right, so, let's start something that we can work with. I think, I do have, two models I'll be testing. The smaller one, which is the 258 one, and the other one, which is having that billion parameter. Okay, just to show out the results.
Krish NAik: Now, I think for this purpose, we'll be using the,
Krish NAik: top technical report, so this is the report. Okay, and I'll be showing you this report, and we'll be doing the comparison parallel.
Krish NAik: King.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So, I think, this is visible for everyone, okay? So, first of all, let me connect it with the runtime.
Krish NAik: And don't ask for the notebook. Once I have successfully executed, then I'm sure.
Krish NAik: Because even in this page, a lot of deprecated stuff are there, so whatever the things are there, I will delete it. Okay?
Krish NAik: First of all, I'm doing, like, the installation of Docklink.
Krish NAik: Alright, what is this? Warning Dockling 2.0 does not provide that extra… Okay, so, like, I was looking for the VLM support. I think if I do end Docklink VLM, so that will also
Krish NAik: So, pretty much, I think, now, most of the things, yes, NVIDIA CUDA, I know the VLM support, for running the model is available.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the first of all, I will be going ahead with a CLI-based approach, okay? Because, first of all, I need to really check it works or not. Okay, so let me just execute this. This will take some time, and I'm using VLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, the visual model, which is 258MB, okay, and we'll be looking into the results.
Krish NAik: So, it will be throwing me, so here I have written docklink to HTML, the output you will get in HTML format, as well as 2MD, 2 markdown, format. Here, in the pipeline, I have told that I'll be using VLM hyphen hyphen, which model? Granite underscore docklink. So, by default, it picks up the 258MB model.
Krish NAik: And then I passed for which document, so this is the research paper link of the docnical, I think DocLink technical report.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it will take some time. First of all, it's loading up all the CUDA-based libraries, and then I think the execution will be done.
Krish NAik: Abhishek is asking, these will be GPU-based everything, the models that I have told, they are based on GPUs.
Krish NAik: If you have them APIs, NVIDIA provides APIs.
Krish NAik: But not everyone.
Krish NAik: For Tamil and Sanhala, look for Indian Oceans, like Surya Oshias.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, like, Sri Lankan, in that way, if you're talking about those languages, Aruna, because I feel that, Surya over here is there, and it's really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm just showing you, because I keep an active track on OCR because this is my main footy, I can say, visual computing-based systems. So, this is the main one, and I think Surya OCR with Hugging Face.
Krish NAik: Really, I think, yes. Vikram is the guy, I think. Even I.
Krish NAik: Vips…
Krish NAik: Where is that one? This is Datalab.2. They have very specific APIs also that they provide in 90-plus languages.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I know Bengali, Hindi, a few things are there, but
Krish NAik: Chinese, Japanese, Arabic, detection, layout, order, table recognition, pretty much all the things are done here. Posted API, where is that Hugging Face page just meet?
Krish NAik: Hugging Face page, let me just open that. In the meantime, you can see this model is taking time, so let's explore something others. Yes, this is the actual Hugging Face model.
Krish NAik: What happened to this one? No, no, no, this is a third party.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Who wouldn't you know.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, as I was talking about the collections, this is the Chandra OCR2. I think, this came, 2-3 days back only. Yesterday, the downloads were 500. Today, it has become 3.9, pretty much one. Okay, this is the latest one. I've been also testing it. Chandra OCR really works good, I can say.
Krish NAik: With respect to the models and others, okay, so you can see this is a quick start. I will suggest try to do an inferencing with VLLMS much faster if you're working with Lightning or Collab.
Krish NAik: Easily you can test the model, okay? So, and the benchmark really looks good.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you try to compare this with some other models, like DOTSOCR, which is from the red team, OLR, Marker, DeepSeek OCR, Mestral API, in some cases, I can say it's performing much better than Mestral OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, with respect to GPT-4U, better than GPT-4U, I can say.
Krish NAik: So, really, you guys can test it out, because, so many things are there, guys. Yeah, okay, so I feel that this is a good one, and with respect to, I think, it came 2-3 days back only. Can you see public models updated 4 days ago?
Krish NAik: So, pretty much a recent one. The thing that I will tell you, everything would be, like, in the past 2 months, everything has been coming.
Krish NAik: Please share the current notebook once I execute, then only, because right now, you can see, this is why I hate Kola.
Krish NAik: It's taking so much of time. I don't know why it's taking so much of time. It's just a 250MB model that I am trying to load.
Krish NAik: But with respect to GPU RAM, okay.
Krish NAik: It takes time to load up models, that's the main thing.
Krish NAik: It's a one-time thing, everything… the same thing you can do in implementation.
Krish NAik: The other busier that came is that, from Baidu it was.
Krish NAik: R.
Krish NAik: For what that means. Wow.
Krish NAik: I have to check once my local, because for implementation, I have actually tested it out.
Krish NAik: dots OCR I have checked, then I have worked with, okay, Q1?
Krish NAik: This also came one.
Krish NAik: And yes, this is the other OCS that I was talking about.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is also one of the recent ones. Okay, I think in the last one week, this has also been released. So the number of downloads are lesser right now, but I feel that
Krish NAik: It's really good. Okay, I've tested it. Really, really good.
Krish NAik: Right now, this is the number one model in the PUMI dock benchmark, so this is the actual benchmark. Okay, and in that, I feel that this is, better than Gemini 3 Pro.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it has also 192 languages, so Aruna, you can check that. Very specifically, you have the support. But Tamil, I know it can be there, but for Sanala, not sure about.
Krish NAik: Layout as a thought, yes. But in CPU, really, these type of systems take a lot of time.
Krish NAik: to do, I can say, the…
Krish NAik: inferencing, at least, because these are pre-trained models. All you need to do is the inferencing, but having a system, or if you're working with, spaces, if you have a Hugging Face Pro account, I think which charges you close to $9, then actually you can do a lot of testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, the other one that came this week…
Krish NAik: Everything that I am telling the dot OCR,
Krish NAik: This is the other one.
Krish NAik: From the red, yes, the red node team, I think, 12.OCR, 1.5.
Krish NAik: Yes, the red node, the red team.
Krish NAik: This is also recently that came around.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here they have launched a concept about MOCR.
Krish NAik: And I feel that, yes, this is multimodal OCR,
Krish NAik: If you look into this model, I was actually testing it out, and I felt that, yes, this is also… the results are good.
Krish NAik: And this is the archived paper, and they have actually focused on multimodal document positive. Can you see here? The name is multimodal, Osir, that's why they have focused on MOCR, pass anything from documents.
Krish NAik: really the setup attributes that they have provided. Okay, in this paper, I feel that it's also a good one. Really, like, this
Krish NAik: space is much more about research. It's not, like, one shot.
Krish NAik: You can see 13 March 2026, the actual paper launch, and with respect to model everything, everything that happened. So, whatever the things that I'm telling you right now happened in the past 1-2 weeks. Pretty much state-of-the-art stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a good one. This paper, you can actually take some time with respect to text parsing, graphical bridge parsing, every option is there. Okay, and the results are good. Yes, it takes a lot of time in my local. Later on, I have switched it and checked it, and Lightning AI, that is also good.
Krish NAik: So this is really a high-resolution vision encoders that have been used with higher resolution inputs, so I can say that it's better, but really, you need to test it out. Okay, according to your documents, whether it works or not, it's very hard to say.
Krish NAik: All right, then, if I say something… okay, now these are all OCR-based systems. Okay, then, Nemotron Parse is there. Nemotron Parse.
Krish NAik: That is, I think last year this came.
Krish NAik: Pneumotron pass… 1.2, let's take this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see this is a single model to understand document semantics, extract text, table elements, everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is completely open source, and this also you can use, I feel that
Krish NAik: in this Nemotron parse paper.
Krish NAik: Get me more, huh?
Krish NAik: Bar speaker.
Krish NAik: Here, also, they have compared a lot of OCR-based systems.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. I think, the doppeling part is done. Okay, so let's quickly do a common…
Krish NAik: This is my main DocLink paper, and let's look into the markdown file, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm focusing on the Markdown file. I don't need this stuff, how to collapse? Yes, this collapse is done.
Krish NAik: That's so weird.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now this is the result of the model. So, I can say that, yes, docking an efficient, open-source toolkit, AI-driven document conversion.
Krish NAik: Alright, the name of the researchers came correct.
Krish NAik: IBM Research, Switzerland, okay, alright, this part is correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… now, when I look into this part, we introduce Dockling and easy to use, find till this point, filled processing documents.
Krish NAik: Tell Processing Documents.
Krish NAik: After that, how… why this came so many times? In the paper, in the paper, in the paper. In this paper, we present.
Krish NAik: Now, this is where I feel that…
Krish NAik: A lot of times, the same text came. Can I say that? See, guys.
Krish NAik: Because here, I feel that it has failed.
Krish NAik: Because I need to show you the output, so whenever you are looking into the output, try to analyze.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, it doesn't work for me in this case, because from this part, the open source community
Krish NAik: In this paper, we present in this paper. Now, that part, we present a noble approach, we present a noble approach. Again, so many times it failed, okay? Now, if I look into the next part, image has been correctly extracted.
Krish NAik: But, alright, the extra portions have been capped out.
Krish NAik: And I can say that, okay, fine, at least the image parsing is correct.
Krish NAik: not a lot of wrong things are there. But, okay, after that, Figure 1KH, one docklink came here. So, little bit, I feel that
Krish NAik: Things are wrong, one dockling came, but I've actually docklinked.
Krish NAik: Alright, two hallucinations, conversion.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this part, I feel that this is a separate thing. When you actually do a parsing.
Krish NAik: it becomes harder to understand that you start from two hallucinations. So, really, this can create an issue.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, design and architecture. Again, so many times, design and architecture came. Again, failed, failed.
Krish NAik: Okay, then 4.1. Everything in one shot they have written, fine. This is a lightweight model, okay? So, like, then also I'm impressed with the model, because later on, if I really switch to something billion parameters, for sure it will work. This is only a million.
Krish NAik: Parser backends, this part. Okay, our table was there, I can understand from here, some type of table.
Krish NAik: Let's look into the table path.
Krish NAik: asset version, Asset version layout.
Krish NAik: Okay, it has really, like, if I look into the table, unstructured highlights, the structure of the table is not maintained, but
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: it has fetched the data. Then, the next images, per category, this is where the second image has been somehow cropped and patched together
Krish NAik: Then, methodology, okay, this is the part. Again, this part, some here, conversion, references, really, again, so many times the GitHub repo is a good place to start, but really, I feel that, it should have more info.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, yes, references is actually… now, this is really not working.
Krish NAik: So this is a simple testing, so whenever you are doing, please always do the testing, it's very, very important.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: The testing is important. So, simply, this is a frailty case.
Krish NAik: It means that, yes, it works good, but right now, really, I passed an academic paper. A lot of other infographics are there, graphic-based elements are there, but it really didn't work. So, let's skip this.
Krish NAik: So, simply, I will say that this is a failed one. I won't be utilizing this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is, again, the Pythonic implementation, leave this part I don't want.
Krish NAik: This is a VLM-based inferencing, leave this part, not important.
Krish NAik: already.
Krish NAik: Because I've been testing multiple ones, but I think, the main model, the bigger model, actually, that one, I will be using this time. So let me install, I think, DocLink 4 is available in my system.
Krish NAik: the dock layout with Travelformers.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is a two layout system that I am actually moving into right now. Rather than… so this time, the model will be much more bigger. Let's look into the performance of the bigger model.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is purely a Python-based, implementation. Last time, it was a CLI-based implementation. Yeah, so I will, do the execution, and this is the second model from the Granite family having the billion parameter. Let me test how the results we are getting.
Krish NAik: Okay, so actually, like, a few things are there that you really, don't need to work on.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a few cells, I will just delete, it's not actually required.
Krish NAik: Okay, because these are VLLM, if you're working with VLLM, how many of you know about VLLM?
Krish NAik: If you want to serve an LLM, then VLLM is used.
Krish NAik: VLM… anybody has used VA…
Krish NAik: Now, this is a package I prefer if you're working with… that actually helps you for model serving. If anybody has worked with model serving.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, simple setup. If you don't know about this, so this is just… actually helps you to get better throughput, so this is actually used in production.
Krish NAik: So that's why I've kept that quanto. But, just remember, the first cell.
Krish NAik: and only the last one. That needs to be executed. Okay, I think the execution has been done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this time, rather than using the Knight DockLink 250, it can be a dock layout model with an VLM table format, so two different models have been used, actually, guys. Okay, now let's look into the output here. It looks like the execution has been done. Okay, now.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the MD file. Okay, so let's close this, and let's try to analyze.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is. Okay, so docklink, efficient, alright, fine. Now, this is the name of the authors, got extracted correctly.
Krish NAik: abstract part with repository, all right. I cannot see any type of repetitions like last time, when we saw that in this paper we proposed so many times. Okay, the introduction part, yeah, it's good.
Krish NAik: converting documents, this part. Now, with DocLink, can you see it handles the layout also in a great way?
Krish NAik: Okay, the points have been maintained, state-of-the-art. This image is much better, like, like the last time that I have used. Okay, now this is a really, dual-stage-based implementation. I feel that the result looks better here.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your, design and architecture part. Okay, because yes, the figure 1 has been kept in a separate thing, and then susceptibility to hallucinations. At least somehow better, I can say, if I actually try to pick it up, so a chunking strategy will work better on this markdown file.
Krish NAik: Design and architecture, okay, now, yes, this looks good. Then comes the docklink document. Again, this is good. The parser backend, this looks good. 3.3 pipelines.
Krish NAik: Okay, the power backend with respect to pipelines. Really, I would say, the AI models.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, performing better, better. Now, with respect to the table, yes, I will say that the table here is better as compared to last time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, the images are maintained. Last time, if you remember, the image was cut off.
Krish NAik: Okay, benching strategy, results. Okay, applications, ecosystems, this is where images have been rendered. Last time, if you remember, the reference section totally failed. This time, the reference section is exactly the correct.
Krish NAik: So this is a two-model-based system, the dock layout with travel forms, okay? And really, I will say, this worked really great.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now I'll be sharing the notebook, you guys can do the testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, just execute the first and the last step. Nothing in between, because it's not required, actually.
Krish NAik: Okay? The first one, the CLI command, and then you can execute that.
Krish NAik: So, now I've done the testing, and I have shown you one of the things from you.
Krish NAik: Motaza is asking, which cost-effective option will you suggest? Will you use to test different implementations, Google Update or Hugging? No, no, actually, what happens now in Hugging phase, most of the times, if you're working with, let's take .osa.
Krish NAik: Okay, now here you will be having spaces, if they have provided spaces. So, for some models, you will be getting spaces. So, let's take, like,
Krish NAik: If I go ahead with… everybody doesn't provide spaces, but soon spaces will come.
Krish NAik: Because paper, this is the collection, two items uploaded, no. So let's go into… so, if you have that paid one, you can actually work with spaces.
Krish NAik: So I think, what is the other one? I think Surya, yeah. So I'm just telling… data library.
Krish NAik: This is the new model, so actually, when you do it, you don't really need to do a local setup. Can you see the spaces here from Vector? So, actually, it will run a GPU for you, and then you can actually do the inferencing. That is the benefit of getting a Hugging Face pro.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you're really doing a lot of R&D, these are actually for R&D guys, much more, I feel. There are much more options. So, for example, if you want to go with this, let me take, I think, my documents…
Krish NAik: Something, okay?
Krish NAik: test image… okay, yes, this is a test image. Let me pass this one, okay?
Krish NAik: And, let me run the notes here. So, actually, you have already 3 bed spaces, so a 0 GP unit.
Krish NAik: Now, again, if you try to upload, then it will say that your free limit is done, so every day, I think only one 0 GPU unit that can be used.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it will take some time now, so that says only the added benefit.
Krish NAik: If somebody has a GPU, it's much better, right?
Krish NAik: Okay, but if you don't have a GPU, then getting the inferencing from Unface Pro account, it's actually an
Krish NAik: This is actually initializing the system, and this is a much bigger model, having 5 billion parameters.
Krish NAik: They have all the major integrations, like webcam and other things, with clipboard and others.
Krish NAik: Alright, so you guys also do the testing?
Krish NAik: Okay, and then let me know. What are the cells? The last cell, and the first cell? Only two things that you need to execute. Other than that, don't execute, because other things are related to, serving of the models, and through that, we were doing this.
Krish NAik: Pratamish, instead of just some API key, even if cost really good, if you want to go with API keys, you can. I am not… IMC, I don't talk about, like, closed source stuff.
Krish NAik: It really doesn't matter. If you want to work with Google Vision API, use it, AWS Strat, nothing else.
Krish NAik: But actually, like, I cannot… because I feel that these are much better than those.
Krish NAik: That's why research matters. Later on, these type of things, what AWS and Google will do, they will actually look into their implementation, they will extract, they will attach it in their own.
Krish NAik: That's how they upgrade models.
Krish NAik: No API cases are required right now.
Krish NAik: Everything that I'm showing is pretty much open source stuff.
Krish NAik: When APIs will come, I will tell you.
Krish NAik: And here, if I'll actually look into the results, I will say that the markdown output
Krish NAik: Okay, the table has been, correctly. Okay, now this is in the format of, the markdown. I can see the table tag, table 1,
Krish NAik: I can say the results are good, actually.
Krish NAik: Because this is OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the OCR… Layout.
Krish NAik: This is correctly coming, I feel that, till the… the result looks good.
Krish NAik: But simply, you guys can also test it out. Then later on, we will be exploring something else also.
Krish NAik: Yes, but everyone can't do the dev on their system. You really don't need to do the dev, Prathamesh. Like, get a… at least, like, two options are there, you should have a GPU.
Krish NAik: If you don't have a GPU, then R&D is not… then actually consumption of LLMs or the OCR APIs is much better. And these things don't provide, like, I think few of them will provide APIs. I think they have a… but for APIs, you need to, again, pay money.
Krish NAik: So, whichever way you want to do it.
Krish NAik: I will be exploring, don't worry, Mestral OCR also.
Krish NAik: After this, once you guys have done this part, let me know, then we'll be going ahead with my shop.
Krish NAik: I think Mestral has a direct one, rather than
Krish NAik: doing a lot of Streamlit and others, I think, Mr…
Krish NAik: If there is a direct demo, then I really don't need to… Okay, I can see… set up an API key. Okay, yes, somebody has kept it.
Krish NAik: Actually, the layout detection, where it fails in that case. Let me see, actually, if we can do it here.
Krish NAik: This is the web page, and they are with multiple languages. Enterprise, for sure.
Krish NAik: Okay, and they have told that it's better than others?
Krish NAik: So, widely used.
Krish NAik: Okay, once you have done the testing of docklinks, please let me know, can I proceed ahead with the next one?
Krish NAik: Everybody please sign up in Mistral and get an API key.
Krish NAik: API key is required.
Krish NAik: I won't share the draft only. It will come around April…
Krish NAik: First week or, second week.
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, please let me know the Dockling part you executed.
Krish NAik: Because this is direct model running and doing the inference.
Krish NAik: Actually, the research is in the model, the dock layout model, and the table formats. That is the actual research part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so smaller models, for sure they won't work. Bigger models are working fine from the docklink part.
Krish NAik: So, like, try to get an API key, I think I will be having…
Krish NAik: One API key, let me just open here.
Krish NAik: This is, Mestral OCR, just feet.
Krish NAik: Do I have an API key with me, or must try?
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: I was working with Nestral last week. Let me just get, one.
Krish NAik: Cheers.
Krish NAik: Nemo API limitless…
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody please sign up into Mistral and get an MBA. It's pretty much easy, I think. You can click on Try Studio, okay, and there you can actually do a login, do this.
Krish NAik: Here, you will be having the API key section. Please go to the API key section and create an API.
Krish NAik: Now you can actually paste your simple API here, okay? Set the API key.
Krish NAik: It's telling enter a valid API key, really, this is working or not, I'm not sure.
Krish NAik: Let me see by testing and engage. Because this is just a space of a random guy. I thought it will work, but, really…
Krish NAik: not working. Leave it.
Krish NAik: Let's go with the studio padding.
Krish NAik: A lot of vision-capable modernistrals have, like, recently launched in the past one year, but a lot of new updates are not coming.
Krish NAik: So somehow, as this is much more enterprise level, so the updates is much lesser.
Krish NAik: they do release some open-source models, but really, the integration into their main enterprise, I feel that it really takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now let me upload a document. Let me get, something like a docklink report, I think it will work multimodal.
Krish NAik: Where I have that PDF multimodal, right.
Krish NAik: I don't think I ever do.
Krish NAik: So right now, just check out their studios, and from their studios, you'll actually, like, I feel that
Krish NAik: You'll be getting the output.
Krish NAik: So, like, model… which one? This is the latest version, I think, that they have. Okay, so directly run it. This is purely enterprise.
Krish NAik: And just check that, whether you are… because I feel the results that you get here is really good.
Krish NAik: Really, really, really good.
Krish NAik: But with respect to, the layout detection, somehow I feel that
Krish NAik: That part can be towards the lower side.
Krish NAik: With respect to this one, I really feel that… let me just increase this one.
Krish NAik: Yes, the result looks good to me.
Krish NAik: The visual future works.
Krish NAik: The references part, also, it has correctly analyzed 1, 2, after that, 3, 4, 5.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the part with respect to… The appendage…
Krish NAik: abstract C1… Now, this is the visual part, see. One is the text output.
Krish NAik: Then, looking into the visual one.
Krish NAik: Based on Markdown. Okay, now this is quite, exactly…
Krish NAik: I can say that. I will say the result is good.
Krish NAik: Plus, this is for sure enterprise.
Krish NAik: Actually, it's better than AWS Dock Intelligence and even with that, but very few organizations work with Mistral. Usually, I feel that
Krish NAik: they use their own internal cloud API service, but the performance is better. Because I feel if you really try to compare AWS, Azure.
Krish NAik: It's very, very close. Like, only, like, 1-2% where I feel that
Krish NAik: Mistral can surpass those systems. So, really, that is the amount of error.
Krish NAik: But, other than that, really, like, it works great.
Krish NAik: Now, actually, like, I don't think they have given a, layout-based analysis
Krish NAik: Okay, because actually, like, even I look for layout-based analysis also, and Vestral OCR actually supports both of the things. It's pretty much like the more from PaaS,
Krish NAik: You can actually look onto the layout also, and then you can look into the…
Krish NAik: Ocr also. So right now, directly, the result that you have seen is pretty much the OCR stuff scene.
Krish NAik: Now, let me just open one's…
Krish NAik: I think, where I do have that.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: I'm just opening the terminal for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I feel that in visual part, sometimes with respect to layout analysis, the result is
Krish NAik: Last time I tested, most of the pages it worked, but in one of the pages, it actually failed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what is the name of the file? Let me just join the scripts.
Krish NAik: Vegetable location.
Krish NAik: Let me stream that… Ron?
Krish NAik: This is the visual lines.
Krish NAik: Mr.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Moved right by intercessor.
Krish NAik: Mr. OCR, extract headers, footers, okay, just wait. I'll be passing it, so this is a simple API call that I'll be making it, and let me just, focus on that one. Extract images, right now. Okay, this is an API call that I'm making, so yes…
Krish NAik: It will take some time, this API is completely free.
Krish NAik: The main part is that layout detection part, because till now, I feel that we have not…
Krish NAik: worked on the… okay, now this is the entire Markdown file.
Krish NAik: And, no image in the regions.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is page 1.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I have, done in that way, that I was actually testing it out for every pages, and based on every page, the test that I have done, I feel that, yes.
Krish NAik: the results with respect to the API is good.
Krish NAik: But, again, like, in some page, there is an image. If you look into, this is an image.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this image, so I can see that, yes, the image has been extracted.
Krish NAik: So this is actually… my main purpose was only to extract images. Similarly, if I go to the last page of the PDF, I know, I think there was another one. Can you see here? Two images, and these two images have been correctly extracted.
Krish NAik: So I feel that, yes, like, this is good, and simply, like, I created this app for my internal testing. Okay, but, I found that the API is really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is something, like, I can suggest that, yes.
Krish NAik: Like, we can work with this in production, directly, yeah.
Krish NAik: All right, now, Mr. AloCR, please, everybody, please do the testing. You don't need the Streamlit app, directly do it there only. Okay?
Krish NAik: Yes, we are not using any OCR on that one, rather than it will be the model, more than one
Krish NAik: We are not using Rapid OCR, ECOCR, those are the default
Krish NAik: fallback. That's why we don't want to install.
Krish NAik: Huh…
Krish NAik: Alright, this part is done. Now, I will show with respect to Nemo Tone Pass, because that is also a good one. So, let me just close this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this… measuring lines.
Krish NAik: Nemo… what is the name of the file? Visualize underscore pars right there.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is actually the Nemotron Pass PDF inspector I was actually working. This model is completely open source, you can download it from Hugging Face, and you can
Krish NAik: Please share the API key. Why? I will share, Satish. You have to get your own API key.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, let me just upload a PDF.
Krish NAik: Initially, you see, these are all the API tests that I am doing, so parse all these pages. Right now, it will take some time.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because this is an unified model right now, similarly the enterprise one, but this is much better for layout analysis, I can say, rather than directly running an OCR on top of the system. Because if something is Enterprise you have to handle, by default, they will be handling both the things, the layout analysis, as well as the
Krish NAik: Yor vociara.
Krish NAik: Any enterprise solutions that you are working with.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is actually, I feel that, how many of you can see that I have
Krish NAik: Actually, like, the return type of the model is actually a bounding box.
Krish NAik: So, when I work with bounding boxes much more, can you see that, I'm getting the results? This is layout analysis.
Krish NAik: This is not who theory, you have to understand. So, first of all, like, I have multiple legends here. So, for this particular page, okay, so these are the different attributes which have been run.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the results of Nemotron PARS. Similarly, if I go to, like, page 4, okay, you can see. Now, this is pure layout analysis.
Krish NAik: Okay, now if I go to page 5… okay, now this is a table which has been detected. Similarly, you can look into that, okay, in some part, like, okay, the table also came into the picture, so based on that, yes, table is there.
Krish NAik: And now, okay, now let's look into page 9.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, this is the part where it actually failed, I think.
Krish NAik: With respect to this particular page, the Motron Pass.
Krish NAik: But let's look into page 8. Again, this is where it failed. Can you see here, so many bounding boxes?
Krish NAik: It means that I need some type of post-processing element here.
Krish NAik: Because this model is 3 open source, but most of the enterprise-based solutions, they do have a post-processing output.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, you need to really handle this type of scenarios, if the return type of the model is something. And here I can actually see. So, this is from NVIDIA Animotron Parse.
Krish NAik: their best OCR model, I can say, tell me.
Krish NAik: the unified model, not OCR model, the unified model that they have built. So, actually, you can go into, like, you can check out the NVB area models also.
Krish NAik: NVIDIA.
Krish NAik: build.
Krish NAik: I think, trial name appears.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see here, okay, so you have a lot of different type of models. Explore more models, I'm just looking into.
Krish NAik: So, from here, if you go with pass…
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is Nimotron Pass, which came 4 months back.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the old model that I have actually tested it. Text and table extraction.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is really good in that, but sometimes I feel that it fails.
Krish NAik: Okay. Similarly, if you are working with layout, Okay, so layout.
Krish NAik: NVIDIA has everything, the stack of NVIDIA is really good, but again, like,
Krish NAik: So this is the Nemotron OCR, and this is the V1 version. This came last week.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is also… I feel that only last week came, you guys can actually use it, you can get an API key, and you can set up this stuff. Okay, so again, API keys are available.
Krish NAik: Layout… other than layout, for table also, I think they have a very specific model for table detection.
Krish NAik: But everything in NVIDIA, there is a model for the… Cable 1?
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see table structure V1, page elements V3?
Krish NAik: These are actually used for table detection, charts, titles, okay, table structure one. If you are actually working with the NVIDIA RAC blueprint, if you remember… how many of you remember the NVIDIA
Krish NAik: rack blueprint I showed.
Krish NAik: there, actually, if you do the setup in a GPU, okay, there, all these models will be consumed.
Krish NAik: Okay, you will be doing a single Docker Compose, and then that will come. Methesh is asking, no, no, this is not a stream later. This is a pure NVIDIA interface. So here, for everything, you have a model.
Krish NAik: Okay, and for table structure one, one year ago, there has not been a lot of updates on the table structure, because it really works.
Krish NAik: But 2 weeks ago, this model actually came, the table structure P1, which can be used.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, I can say that, yes, models are coming, but yes, this is pure OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, but if you want to do layout analysis with that one, then you have the path. So, unified models or the combo? Which one you want, you really need to decide. If I do, like, I have to make a combo of a table from here with a noose here.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, like, you guys can do the testing. Are you paid? Yes. No, no, the model is available for free, in Hugging Face. I told you in video, this is…
Krish NAik: Model is available, there is no issue. Model, you can download and you can run it. These are open source models.
Krish NAik: Mistral is only enterprise, till now that I have shown. Other than everything else, purely opens.
Krish NAik: whatever the things that I have told, like GLM or CR, then came your, panel… okay, because in our project, I will be working with
Krish NAik: PP.Layouts, you can see here, this came… this is a layout analysis model, okay, and this layout analysis model, I will be doing the integration. Okay, so I think this came around, when I look into the, technical report ones, okay? Just wait.
Krish NAik: This is, recent only, not very old.
Krish NAik: Because in our project, I'll be utilizing PP1.
Krish NAik: Because if you really work with a direct API, it doesn't make sense, actually.
Krish NAik: Because you really need to understand how things are being handled. Okay, this is the Paddle OCR VL. Okay, now this OCR actually uses the PP detection layout internally. Okay, so what I will do, I want to be using the paddle OCR VL. Rather than from this paper, I'll be extracting, I'll be getting only the PP detection layout V3.
Krish NAik: Okay, for layout analysis.
Krish NAik: And I'll be working with the, GLM OCR technical report
Krish NAik: Okay? Whatever the thing that I have actually used is pretty much state-of-the-art for your project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is 16th March 2026.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, like, they have done the integration with, pp.layoutv3. As you can see, a direct integration is there in their SDK, so, like, I'll be using this one, okay? But, right now, even the, like, the Baidu OCR data showed, it performed better than GN.
Krish NAik: Okay, but, the integration of direct analysis is available, so I will be picking up GLM in your project. It has an API, you can run it in OLAMA, both the benefits, you get it, so I will prefer GLM much more.
Krish NAik: Local-based inferencing should be better.
Krish NAik: Those are, like, you can get the direct API, Satish.
Krish NAik: Okay, it was just, I was showing you for the main purpose, because sometimes I have to do visual inspection and debugging for those things. Otherwise, direct APIs are there, you can directly work with these APIs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is in your project, this will be there. That's why, yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I have… I have added an ULAMA support, JLM provides API also the Z API.
Krish NAik: They have it. So, like, if you're really working with the NVIDIA stack, and this is a recent model that came with the 120 billion parameter last week, NimoTurn 3, this is also a really good model which can be actually hosted for local inferencing.
Krish NAik: Okay, now comes, see, like, we have defined Most of the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, now we will be working with… Minorly.
Krish NAik: Because, as I'm showing you so many things.
Krish NAik: My favorite stack, which is the mini root that we'll be working with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is minor U, and when I say that, it's good, it's actually used in production.
Krish NAik: Can you see the number of staff? It's something like, when you see the staff, you know that the adoption
Krish NAik: This is from Shanghai Labs, Shanghai AI Labs, okay, with Open Data Lab. Majorly the research, I can say. Okay, but the number of stars is really, really high. The output is really, really good, okay? So, let's start with the minor implementation.
Krish NAik: So yeah, for minor review, I need a GPU. Without a GPU, I cannot do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything you can do it here. For everything, they have a model. They have a VLM, they have their OCR model, they have layout analysis model, everything is available in Minario. Actually, Minaryu uses the Yolodoc layout model.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… before starting, let's get with the minority docs, and we'll be testing the CLI part first of all.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please open your, I think, minor, you just wait. Let me try it in collab. If it works, I'm not really sure that in collab it will work or not, but let me see.
Krish NAik: Let me get a new one.
Krish NAik: Now, this part, always remember for multimodal rack, what is the main decision? Blindly, like, try to go with APIs better.
Krish NAik: But, really, like, you have to parse the results.
Krish NAik: So, if your document parsing is wrong, multimodal rack pipelines failed.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here they are talking about getting started. Let's get started from here. So, quick usage.
Krish NAik: So, they are telling, please do the installation.
Krish NAik: Out the port, and then they have everything here.
Krish NAik: Click start.
Krish NAik: Okay, give it PIP install, so I have PIP, minor review all I will be doing.
Krish NAik: This, you cannot actually run it locally. It has a lot of dependencies.
Krish NAik: So, it has a requirement.txt file, so that really takes a lot of time. And now, when I'll be actually, passing, I think from my last video, I can get that attention…
Krish NAik: Or the toppling.
Krish NAik: The installation will take some time, so just wait.
Krish NAik: No, minor use a two-stage pipeline, but it uses Intel in two different models.
Krish NAik: For document layout detection, Minery uses, DocLayout YOLO.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is the model.
Krish NAik: I haven't having sleep yesterday's face.
Krish NAik: There are multiple… your dock layout YOU, can you see?
Krish NAik: like, this is a dataset of that, but you have a doc layout YOLO-based model, which is used by my name.
Krish NAik: There also, and it has a separate VLM also.
Krish NAik: the OCR model is developed.
Krish NAik: So it's two-stage pipeline, miner… Till now, for, minor U, how much execution?
Krish NAik: Actually, a lot of things, this paper install really takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Okay, restart the session, fine.
Krish NAik: You know?
Krish NAik: I hope this is the PDF correctly, yeah, the PDF is looking fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, the input path, let me just pass it, copy path…
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the input path.
Krish NAik: And output path, where you want. Just let's keep a dot for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you will see the GPU.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now the ZPU users will come, so just wait, 2 to 3 minutes, we'll…
Krish NAik: All these models are available in Agingface, so, like, pretty much open source stuff.
Krish NAik: Defin is asking, do we need to do this? Totally your wish. If you want, you can.
Krish NAik: Because later on, I'll be sharing the notebook, so directly connected.
Krish NAik: Till now, I can see GPU, it means that the models are getting downloaded.
Krish NAik: Can you see how many model.steps tells us are there?
Krish NAik: Just wait, Mitesh, just wait. If it doesn't work in collab, I will switch to Lightning, okay? So just wait.
Krish NAik: You know, I'm feeling that so many 22222 that I saw now, so I feel that, the CUDA might crash, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Just wheat.
Krish NAik: Just open GitHub, no. Just write minor u GitHub.
Krish NAik: And from there, so this is the right minor GitHub, and this is the documentation.
Krish NAik: Do it, search by yourself, guys, at least.
Krish NAik: Now, I've shared it in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, now detected a platform CUDA.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Now the GPU will be used.
Krish NAik: Shini Vasarau, it's, I'm sharing mine. It's a Notion, it's APP.
Krish NAik: Add the red question only.
Krish NAik: Let me send some meals.
Krish NAik: Already. Okay, the GPU RAM, 6GB.
Krish NAik: Already?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, everything, PPT, POT, everything will work. Just be sure, like, if you're working with me, generally, most of the OCRs intake is image or PDF files. You can convert a PPT into a PDF or image, and then you can do that.
Krish NAik: That is a small thing.
Krish NAik: I'm using the VLLM engine right now for inferencing.
Krish NAik: For model serving, not using the transformers, I feel that it's better.
Krish NAik: Only two commands are required, one installation command, one running command, from the docs that I have taken.
Krish NAik: Previously, the project Minorio was called as Magic PDF.
Krish NAik: Later on, they have renamed it to Minor.
Krish NAik: But if you have EULM and EY specification, just be sure, whether you have diagrams based.
Krish NAik: For diagrams and others, I will prefer Kolf Pali much more.
Krish NAik: In collab, it's a bit slower, I feel that it can be faster.
Krish NAik: In… you know, lightning.
Krish NAik: Somehow, this is a free infrastructure, so yes, limitations are there.
Krish NAik: Can you see parallel OCR model?
Krish NAik: That came in.
Krish NAik: Now, YOLO model, Now, you minor net model, many models will be downloaded now.
Krish NAik: Alright, so shutting down client. Okay, I can see my local output is in this folder, which got created based on the PDF name. Now, hybrid auto is the strategy through which we have done the inferencing. There are multiple strategies, like the pipeline strategy.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for now, okay, and let me show you the PDF. There will be a PDF file with layout.pd, okay? So I will just open this one.
Krish NAik: And here you have all the images which are being extracted. If I click on this, you will see the images that are being there. Can you see the docklink image?
Krish NAik: Second.
Krish NAik: the table has an image, then this is an image, okay, this is an image. Later on, I can actually pass this to a VLLM, okay, to generate much more detailed captions, guys.
Krish NAik: So, that's why. Now, I think I downloaded the PDF, layout PDF, let me just show you the layout PDF, yes. Can you see now how the PDF has been done?
Krish NAik: Really, like, this is, like, really, really good, with respect to not a single mistake.
Krish NAik: In some cases, like, I told, like, Nimotron pass and others fail, but this is really good when I look into the results of the layout analysis.
Krish NAik: That's why my favorite is binary.
Krish NAik: when I want to work with these type of systems. Okay, and with respect to each referral says each and everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait, I will be sharing you the notebook, so you guys also do the inferencing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I knew you.
Krish NAik: test.
Krish NAik: But, that's the thing, you need a GP.
Krish NAik: without a GPU, you cannot do it.
Krish NAik: Yes, all these models, Murthas, are returned bounding boxes.
Krish NAik: Every one. Okay, so if I show you, you can look into content list JSON v2. This is the file, and you will see here, bounding boxes.
Krish NAik: Actually, if I have mounting boxes with me, I can manipulate anything.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm telling you, where you have the mounting box information, what is the content type, okay, everything, like your paragraph, whether it's there.
Krish NAik: You will get majorly list. Within this, you have a text, some points, Okay, so what detailed…
Krish NAik: Now, this is one of my production choice.
Krish NAik: really works good, I guess.
Krish NAik: And then I can actually go ahead for chunking and other things.
Krish NAik: So, this is the content, so please do have a check on the content.json also.
Krish NAik: This is a markdown file.
Krish NAik: If you want to look into the Markdown file, be sure here, you won't see the images, because in their rendering part, they don't render images here. But actually, they have the information of the images.
Krish NAik: Actually, what I can do, this folder, I can actually pass it to the VLLM, and I can generate all the captions. So, they don't keep it.
Krish NAik: But fine. Later on, I can add and patch and I can do it. Chetan, it's a one-time activity, right? Once you parse all info and save, it's only inference letter.
Krish NAik: It's one-time activity, right? Once you parse all info and save it, yes. Because the next part, after parsing is the chunky.
Krish NAik: Then comes your normal rack, chunking, embedding, those type of things that will come.
Krish NAik: Rabba Jyoti, for the next steps, all GPG files will be input instead of the… yes, correct. See, I already have the text information with me. So, yes, I don't need anything. So, what I will do, for these images, I will be sending it to the VLN, okay? And then, I'll be looking into
Krish NAik: the captions. I'll be generating captions, basically. Now, let's take another one, I think,
Krish NAik: If I try to do it, just wait.
Krish NAik: So this I have showed for an example, let's take another one.
Krish NAik: So, I think I have something as,
Krish NAik: Archive, attention is all you need. Okay, so let's take another PDF. This is a bigger PDF. Attention is all you need. Let's, get the code.
Krish NAik: Just, I will show you other papers also, then you will feel that.
Krish NAik: Really, like, the output is really good.
Krish NAik: Now, this time, the inferencing will be much faster, because the models are available in your local, so quickly, the inferencing will be done.
Krish NAik: Yes, the folder will be automatically created, no?
Krish NAik: I have selected dot. If you remember dot, dot means the current projector.
Krish NAik: Satish, if you're not, use PWT. In that case, it will give you a better entry.
Krish NAik: Let me show you the attention is all you need paper also. Like, that is a longer paper as compared to the DockerLink technical report.
Krish NAik: Okay, 6GB RAM. 6GB of VRAM around, it's utilizing it.
Krish NAik: Okay…
Krish NAik: Yes, Cheta, Minery has 56K stars, that's my tool, no? People use it in production, Minery.
Krish NAik: What is the benefit of this? Just think about if you have a different documentation pipe.
Krish NAik: And in that pipeline, fine, you are using a GPU. Other than that, in the entire pipeline, you don't need a GPU.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Now, this is only the requirement of the documentation pipeline.
Krish NAik: Not your query pipeline.
Krish NAik: Because in both of the pipelines, there's only one GPU is required.
Krish NAik: So, what you do? So, generally, somebody can take a serverless GPU,
Krish NAik: like, on demand, if you are actually doing it, fine. Take a serverless, it will be much cheaper. Okay.
Krish NAik: And from there, you can do an implementation. So, like, you can create a cron job, every 24 hours, whenever the documents are there, you are actually using the GPU, and then GPU is switched off. Every time you are not utilizing the GPU.
Krish NAik: So that is the added benefit.
Krish NAik: Yes, it is used in production, the look into the stars.
Krish NAik: Like, Vijay, anything more than 10K stars, I can say that people have started using it in production.
Krish NAik: My interviews are really good.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm showing you an inference, then finally.
Krish NAik: an overall system of RAG data to be looking into.
Krish NAik: Yes, already 12.30, so I think today we cannot continue.
Krish NAik: But if I share the notebook, can you guys do it by yourself?
Krish NAik: Because it's pretty much execution only. I built the entire pipeline, you guys just need to do the execution and nothing.
Krish NAik: There, I have kept the entire, pipeline operated.
Krish NAik: Loading the model takes so much of time, sir.
Krish NAik: Rather than keeping the local… okay, now you can see the output is done. Okay, this is attention, all you need. You will see there is a hybrid autofind. Inside this, you'll be having the PDF.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… attention is all you need layout video. Always look into the layout results. If the layout is correct.
Krish NAik: OCR always performs really good, okay? Now, fine. Here, if I look into… yes…
Krish NAik: This is good. Introduction one, background, model architecture, the image has been resolved, so if you actually look into the folder of the images, the first image that I feel
Krish NAik: The image folder is blank. I thought the images… okay, yes, so many images came. No, that's fine. All equations and everything. So I think the first will be pretty much, this is an, formula.
Krish NAik: Of the learning rate that they have used in the paper, okay, the LR.
Krish NAik: All right, now, next one, let's look into. This is the positional encoding formula, okay, where they are using the sinusoidal, function, sign here. Okay, so in positional encodings, we use…
Krish NAik: Then let's look into, look at another… two functions are there for positional encoding, the sine and cost.
Krish NAik: This is the main, attention formula.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's look into more questions, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, this is your, self-attention.
Krish NAik: block, okay, all the major formulas, I can say equations. This is a table. Table has been extracted correctly. Find, self-attention.
Krish NAik: that connection from Tensor to Tensor Notebook, which has been shown here.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is a multi-year detection, MHA.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, this is the main transformer's clock, the main diagram in the paper. Pretty much, I can see the stuff here, okay? And, like…
Krish NAik: If I look here also, I feel that, yes, these two images with respect to formulas. That's why a separate color is there for everything. Whenever you will say, look into the equations, paragraphs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is better. I feel this is a better result for sure.
Krish NAik: That's it. Dockling… see, dockling with the bigger model really worked. There is no issue there also. But, I feel that this is better. Like, simplicity, it's one preference, it's not like that you can use. Dockling is also used in production, minor view is also used in production.
Krish NAik: So, anyone that you can actually pick it up.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, I've shared the notebook, so you guys can actually test it out with complex PDX, and then let me.
Krish NAik: Yes, so I think it might be the console Lightning AI. I'm just looking into the notebook, okay, so…
Krish NAik: because I do have a notebook prepared.
Krish NAik: For the entire, pipeline, actually.
Krish NAik: I think Vision Model, this is the one.
Krish NAik: Satish can, extract scanned invoices as well, yes.
Krish NAik: Check it out. Everything. Minor, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is actually the pipeline, the entire pipeline for, that I've built. Okay, so later on, you can test it, or it's pretty much the same thing. Okay, so here, everything is there. VectorDV, chunking, everything that I've, kept it in this particular notebook.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, really, like, you can test it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, and like, the same test, if you remember with Kulpali that I have done, I've done it here also.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, now see, these are the image captions. Like, I am passing image one by one, as I told you. Like, I'll be passing all the image captions, okay? So, let me just zoom this.
Krish NAik: So, figure one… okay, so here, yes, this diagram illustrates the architecture. Now, this is the GPT-4U caption. I told you, once I have the images, I'll be generating the captions. That is the same thing that I have done. Now, based on that, the rag chart.
Krish NAik: That I've generated, and even for every chunk, I write the modality also. That this chunk is a representation of an image, or the original text.
Krish NAik: So, in that way, it becomes easier for me to differentiate at a later point. Can you see? Modality image?
Krish NAik: So, actually, like, when I save the right chunk, it actually helps me to understand, okay, now this is actually not a piece of text, rather than this is from the image that we have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly for all of our other images, so here also. Now, this is what? This is the…
Krish NAik: scaled, Dot product.
Krish NAik: In the paper. So, you can see the scale.product attention mechanism. These are all GPT-40-generated captions that I have used.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for every image that I had.
Krish NAik: In that way, it becomes, much better.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: And now, if I show…
Krish NAik: Okay, so… now, I have actually… I was working with different type of elements, guys, so, like, if I show you the final, the total number of elements that have worked with the PDF,
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait.
Krish NAik: So, like, the total number of equations, the total number of figures, the total number of tables, the total number of text.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, a lot of things that I've done. Then comes the embedding part, I have used text embedding 3 small. Here, you can use Gemini, the new model, the Gemini embedding tool. That model will also work, you have no. Then you have a vector store integration. So here, I think I have the implementation, based on Zillis.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can work with the API key, or you can use Quadrant also.
Krish NAik: both the vector databases, and finally comes your retrieval demo part. So here, also, I asked a question from the tables only. If you look, what is the blue score of the transform model based on this one, the base model?
Krish NAik: Okay, and the GPT-40 final answer was 27.3. So from this, I know that yes.
Krish NAik: it worked great, okay?
Krish NAik: then some things with respect to, like, if you want to do evaluation and other stuff, I have kept such things, but really, like, this is the part, because this is purely the multimodal access. To me, this file I will share.
Krish NAik: This is the file that I will share, don't worry. I will download.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, let me upload it in Collab, and I will share it.
Krish NAik: Because this is the task, please do it, then next week I will start
Krish NAik: exactly the… I think the GLM OCR and a few other testing that actually will be doing it in the project.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I have shown you
Krish NAik: Break by break, but again, few things that can be improved here. Okay, and that, later on we'll be talking.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I will add all the notebooks to Notion Room.
Krish NAik: Because from this part, this is actually, like, things become much more tougher.
Krish NAik: Because then… The next one, advanced course, actually, I'll be focusing much more on multimodal stuff.
Krish NAik: I feel that it's much… MOCR-based systems, okay. So, let me share the notebook with you.
Krish NAik: Everything hasn't been tested, and just be sure, I'm using Lightning AI, you are also using Lightning AI.
Krish NAik: In collab, I have not done the testing, so not sure about, but this is how the approach that I have taken. Look at text, chunks, figure, and tables, pretty much in a separate way that I have taken.
Krish NAik: And please look into the JSON file. From the JSON file, you'll be getting everything.
Krish NAik: So, everything, GPU validation, checks, everything, I have kept it. What are the API keys I have used? I have used the embedding model, OpenAI API key, and Vector2Store zillies. If you don't want to use, then you can run a local Docker instance of quadrant. That is the other way around, the local quadrant option.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything out, different type of engines. See, I am working with the hybrid auto engine.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you're actually changing the engine, more VRAM will be required. And this is a pipeline, really, like, you can test it with the pipeline, this is the backend where only CPU will be used, but again, the quality in the results will be dropped.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this part also you can check. So, for example, in our case, let me see if I have the runtime enabled to me. So…
Krish NAik: Let me go with the dockling, one.
Krish NAik: Where is the docklink, docklink, docklink? This is minor U. Here, actually, you can add this hyphen hyphen pipeline at the end.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the documentation, it's already mentioned. So, if you go to the documentation, you can see hyphen B, what is the back end, or the backbone? Oh yeah, that part you can add, and again, you can actually pass it.
Krish NAik: That's so…
Krish NAik: I'm just showing you the CPU-based inference, and so exactly, like, how it might work.
Krish NAik: Let me delete this folder for now.
Krish NAik: Because the same folder will be overwritten, actually, if you don't do it.
Krish NAik: This is the CPU-based inferencing. Right now, I'm just showing you the results exactly how the results look like.
Krish NAik: Is Docklink run-night a single stage or a two-stage? The 258MB model, that's the unified version, but other than that, the last model where you got good results versus the DAX is a two-stage. They use dock layout and table, performance.
Krish NAik: I think, as in my case, I do have a GPU. If GPU is available, I feel that it's overriding the, pipeline one.
Krish NAik: Because really, then you need to test on a sequel.
Krish NAik: Because, I can see my, CUDA got, detected, because I think in their code they have kept it even for CPU detection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Because then the result will be actually the same.
Krish NAik: So, I think this is the auto part. Let me see with respect to this one.
Krish NAik: This should be one, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, this is the one.
Krish NAik: Yeah, also, I would say…
Krish NAik: Because the overwritten, because of that, yes, GPU has been used, I feel, but yes.
Krish NAik: But, somehow, some changes with respect to colors.
Krish NAik: that I feel, which was there. In the other one.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if I go here, in the last part, this actually should be all green.
Krish NAik: But, the attribute type has changed when I look into this one.
Krish NAik: So in that way, generally, like, this is a CPU fine. I know that there will be cons, but actually the CPU-based inferencing is also really working good, I can say. But this part, you can see this is in green color, so this is a different attribute who should actually be under references.
Krish NAik: Okay, so few, cons are there, but really, like, minor you…
Krish NAik: I feel that it's really, really good, and that's why so much stars that take it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything with respect to today's exploring of multiple OCRs, okay, multiple layout analysis, I have given you multiple paradigms for that. Now, in some systems, they use two different OCRs. For example, in some cases, like, some of the OCRs are not really good and handwritten.
Krish NAik: document recognition, handwritten documents, okay, or sometimes with respect to scanned handwritten documents. In those cases, like, you probably might need to switch
Krish NAik: the model.
Krish NAik: Right, so really, like, you need to understand that whether you have this. Like,
Krish NAik: Generally, I've seen people using hybrid engines, where they use two different types of OCRs. One, the
Krish NAik: Padel OCR, the other one with a GLM OCR in that way, like, two OCR, the fallback, because some OCRs are really good and handwritten, but others are not. So really, you need to look into, and you need to do the research, and then you need to, take the final implementation plan.
Krish NAik: Because, till now, the whole idea that I have told, but in our project, even I have used
Krish NAik: A re-ranking also. A VL re-ranking from Quinn.
Krish NAik: Okay, that part, really have not, discussed, but, you have, twin rear ankles.
Krish NAik: Can you see VL, the visual support re-ranking?
Krish NAik: Okay, so I've even taken this one. Okay. Otherwise, an alternate API is also there for, visual re-ranking, because this is different from your text re-ranking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like, based on that, we have… Surya OCR is good, yes, the Surya OCR2 that got launched last week, really is good.
Krish NAik: Imran, you can test it. They have the, paid API levels.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I know Surya OCR is really, really good.
Krish NAik: Because, the work that I've been doing is something like a lot of research that came, okay? This is a model that I was actually testing, this is an unified embedding model, just like Gemini, but completely free.
Krish NAik: And only embed Nemotron. Okay, an unified model for text, image, audio, video, everything that can be handled.
Krish NAik: Okay, rather than going for that option, because I was looking for a single thing which can do everything. So in… for rag-based systems, this is the other one.
Krish NAik: A lot of models that came is something like, from Molmo also came Halen AI research. Okay, they had launched a VL model. Okay, you can use OCRs also on top of that. So this is, open-based data for vision, so…
Krish NAik: This is a lot of things that came in the past one week, so actually I was looking into the papers. Okay, and everything is open source that I have tested it out right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, Chandra OCR, and these are really good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Other than that, this week, what other came, in Hugging Face, Kulpali…
Krish NAik: Okay, so that part already I have pulled…
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the twin fan OCR. Okay, so this also, you can look into this scheme. Just last week, they have added the model. This is from, Baidu. Okay, these models are also that I have tested. They're really great.
Krish NAik: So, like, in the field of OCR, like, everything. This is the DOTS one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the dot family that I told from red node, the red team, that we call it.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, APIs are already there, but I look into open source implementations a lot, so… based on that. So, a lot of new research came, so I spent a lot of time on exploring and looking into the layout analysis. I will say most of them performed really good, so the saturation level that I feel is really there.
Krish NAik: It's not like that, yes.
Krish NAik: Very little change.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: But yes, so in our final one, so everything with visuals that I have added. Okay, and GLM OCR, okay, when I say the GLM OCR GitHub, I think as last week, they published the technical report.
Krish NAik: After that, they have added, like, last week, a lot of things that they have added in there. So, I will be using this SDK of GLM OCR, okay, because this is also state-of-the-art right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this OCR actually supports Olama. It means that you can work with the API, they have an API also, so I already have the API with me, so I have done the testing, but you have the option of doing
Krish NAik: like, OLAMA-based support. Can you see OLAMA is there? So, in your case, it will be completely free. In your local, you can run, and you can actually do all the parsing stuff.
Krish NAik: So that's why I picked up this one. And this one actually integrates PP Detect.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I feel that it's much easier than separately, I don't need a separate model for layout analysis also. By default, pp.layout is integrated in this particular SDK, so I'll be using this SDK in our project.
Krish NAik: Google Doc EI, yes, for handwritten, Microsoft, that one, Microsoft, Doc Intelligence, that is also good. Vision API, Doc EI from Google, that is also good. You can use AWS Tech Extract, that is also good.
Krish NAik: Cloud-based APIs, really, but with respect to updates and other things, pretty much, as you know, enterprise levels, things lesser updates that comes.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so pretty much done for today's topic.
Krish NAik: Okay, so next week, then, we will start a little bit with the project, but the notebook that I have shared, everybody please do the execution of this notebook. In this notebook, nothing is new, but in Phil, how I've built the pipeline, so focus on that part.
Krish NAik: Everybody please spend this week on that notebook. At least if you spent one hour, see, I feel that I've done the entire testing, it should work. If anything breaks, you can let me know in the forum.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I will look, because I have already tested it, last night, so I feel the entire notebook is up and working, but, you can actually have a test on that one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's a complete multimodal rack pipeline, which we will be using in our question. Take it as a reference, because most of the things, like embedding, chunking, those are normal. Only this was the new part, which is parsing. In parsing, two paradigms. One, the cool style, that we call it. The other one is the layout plus OCR style.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, Kohl's style, you have multiple models. Kol Pali is the first model, then you have the latest one, which is the Kohl Quinn, 2.5VL 0.2, that is the best model right now. That is under paradigm E. Paradigm B, the layout analysis, and the OCR. So here, again, two different things.
Krish NAik: Do you have a unified model, or you are working with dual-stage pipelines?
Krish NAik: Okay? So, in this way, because when you are actually working
Krish NAik: before doing any selection, at least you should work in your R&D. That's why I'm telling, always tell that ESU know these things also.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, directly, if you say that I have used this API, it's fine. I'm not telling you, don't use… use the API. But what are the other open source alternates you should know?
Krish NAik: At least, okay? So, for multi-mode, because I feel that for rag-based interview questions, people ask a lot from multi-mode. So that's why explore the different paradigms.
Krish NAik: And then, yeah, in that way, at least people will know that you know the stuff, rather than directly API. Because in API, you have to just parse the JSON output, and then you have to get.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me start taking questions now. So, a few people have raised their hands.
Krish NAik: So I think, Ang Shu is there.
Krish NAik: Pavan is there.
Krish NAik: cheat them instead.
Krish NAik: Just wait, before speaking, just wait. I need to change my speaker, okay? So… Yes, please go ahead.
Chetan: Hey, hi Paul, I'm Chetan here.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Chetan: Yeah, so, yeah, today's session was very interesting. So, just, thought to explain my understanding. So, like, what were sessions we had
Chetan: Till yesterday, right? Or till last week. So it was, like, everywhere we talked about, like, you have got doc, most of the… they… most of these docs were around text, and then we were using embedding models to save that into Ector and database, and then that's where the retriever and inference was coming in picture.
Chetan: So today, like, it goes majorly around PDFs, images, like, Weird.
Krish NAik: charts, diagrams, everything. Like, visual, simply, like, visual things. Visual graphics, that we call it.
Chetan: Correct. So, so that's where, like, we'll have to use this OCR and layout-based models to pass the information, and then you save them into vector data, and from that point onwards, the typical retriever and all things would come as.
Krish NAik: Exactly the same. Only the passing part was different. After parsing, chunking. Then embedding, normal, your pipeline starts.
Chetan: Correct, correct. So… so in a real project, when we come across these type… these type of documents, so then it's… it's the logic which we have to build, right? If it's a .txte, then you follow this pipeline. If it's this kind of a.
Krish NAik: Yes, he…
Chetan: Then you follow the other… Correct.
Chetan: Okay, perfect, okay, thank you. The second question is, I'm having is, like, in enterprise projects, like.
Chetan: we pretty much use Azure tech stack, okay? Now, even though we know that Minor U is a great, framework, or is a great model, right? Especially, it deals with disk layouts and, OCR,
Chetan: then how do we put forward these pictures? Because in my organization, there's an enterprise team who already decides on what tech stack to be used when it comes to AI.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine. Now, see, if anybody is working with cloud APIs, much easier. The response is directly JSON type. See, the in minor use sorted file content JSON, that is the written type of most of the APIs in every cloud. You just need to work and extract from that.
Krish NAik: Because they also perform equally same, but they are not always up to the latest research. That's the only difference. It will also do their work. Now, they have a very specific routing for this, this, this, that's right. But you will really not know what is used behind this, that's the thing.
Krish NAik: So you should always know your open source, because for implementation, Cloud APIs are fine.
Krish NAik: Actually, how things are happening, you should know.
Chetan: Okay, got, got it. And last question is, so we talked about dockling in past, right? So, dockling is a framework, meaning you just add that as a module in your requirement.txt, and then you get those reusable methods in your framework.
Chetan: which you were using for parsing. Now, when you say models, basically, right? It's basically, they are deployed on some server, right? And then you're.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no. Those models are available in Hugging Face, you'll be downloading in your local machine, and then you'll be doing the inferencing.
Chetan: Oh, honey.
Chetan: Yeah, so these layout models and OCRs, so it's like models, they are not elaborated, right? That's…
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. Major, you see, most of the models have their own SDKs. For implementation, it becomes easier for developers, no, so that's why they create SDKs also.
Chetan: Open.
Krish NAik: Everyone will be having their own SDK.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, directly, see, otherwise you have to take that transformer's route.
Krish NAik: You have to install transformer. Every time transformers will be, like, through transformers, you can do it. Like, if you don't have an SDK, go with the transformers based approach.
Chetan: Yep.
Chetan: Okay, yeah, thank you, Bob.
Krish NAik: Got it. Next.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think Abhisheikh raised his hand, Rajat raised his hand, Aang Shu.
Krish NAik: Anyone can go ahead, guys, please go.
Abhishek: Hey, hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm cheap.
Abhishek: So actually, we have created the team for AWS RAP project, and we had a kickoff yesterday, so we just wanted to, you know, have some guidance around how we need to move
Abhishek: Keep it separated.
Krish NAik: But, keep a separate meeting then, okay, on Monday Planet, according to your needs, whenever you are available, let me know.
Krish NAik: a good time, okay? In the mail also, you can let me know, so then I will join that meeting, and I will, connect with you guys, only the leads.
Abhishek: Okay, sure, yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Same thing for Azure Night also, you can do the same stuff.
Krish NAik: Yes, next, Rajat.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, hi Paul, am I audible?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, according to the, today's class, like, we are dealing with the PDFs, or might be, we will.
Krish NAik: Anything, it can be image. See, the main purpose is, if you have any document, visual document, you can convert it into an image. And later on, you can pass it to any OCRB pipeline, sorry.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, so my question revolves around, like, in a normal, production, or in an enterprise, company, so there are, for example, like, we have HR policies or some other things, which also includes text and images, like, the same that we were doing, today. So, is it favorable, or is it advisable to make it separate? Like, we will be
Rajat Khanna: separating out the images, and then, doing processing of it, and then the texting like we do normally in previous classes that we have done. So, over, just the…
Krish NAik: If you feel that those images, like, if somebody's asking the question from those images, that's the main thing you have to think about in your use case. If you feel that the images doesn't matter, then you can go ahead with only text processing. But actually, if you feel that from those images, somebody can do some type of inferencing.
Krish NAik: Any type of questions that can be asked, then you have to process the images also, no?
Rajat Khanna: No, no, so, yeah, so I'm not asking about the, the questions of… based on the images. It's like, we have a… for example, like, we have a storybook, like, okay? So, in that storybook, there are, images related to that story, and also the English or written verbal, verbals of that story. Now, we want to ask the questions based on those stories.
Rajat Khanna: So, do we need to, like, make two separate documents, or only one document, and storing it to VectorDB, like, that will work? So, my… I'm just confused in that.
Krish NAik: During one document, so for example, your one document is one PDF. Correct, yes. Okay. Now, you need just a single collection or an index.
Rajat Khanna: Yes.
Krish NAik: Yes, only a single index is required.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. So, for, so we can, like, the minor U that we, you showed today, so we can just separate out all the images, maintain a normal text document, and store it as an index in VectorDB, and then ask questions.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes. That's why, see, the notebook that I have shared today at the last of the glass, please go through that notebook. In that notebook, while creating your chunks, I always mention the modality of that chunk. Like, whether that chunk belongs to an image or the text.
Krish NAik: In that way, the final answer will be having your citations, or your round trip. Then you can always do the verification.
Rajat Khanna: Got it, okay, okay, okay, but I'll go through that, notebook, because I have still a few questions. After going through that, I can ask…
Krish NAik: Yeah, go through that notebook. For everybody, that notebook is very, very important, so please go through that notebook.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, yeah, thank you, thank you, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think motorized there.
Murtuza Saifee: Hey, Paul.
Murtuza Saifee: Actually, two questions. One is, actually, I'm a little bit confused on that, single-stage and two-stage pipeline things, like.
Murtuza Saifee: How to identify, like, those pieces, so, like, which models are…
Krish NAik: look into the model, say, it's the model that any one is building. In their paper, generally, it is written.
Krish NAik: Okay, similarly, like, which model supports that, which model doesn't supports that? Directly when I don't.
Krish NAik: When I actually go through the reports of those models, then only I come through.
Krish NAik: Because I… because whenever I was doing the research in that way, I asked very specifically that, okay, what are the single-stage models which are available? What are the, like, dual-stage? Because dual-stage is the most common one. We use two different models for two different things, layout analysis and this one. But there are lesser single-stage models in the market.
Krish NAik: And more dual-stage combo that everybody creates.
Murtuza Saifee: So, let's take an example of that, Docklink grenade thing, right? Or Mineru. MinerU has, like, internally, they have an SDK where they are using two-stage things, and internally, they are only deciding, you know, all the layouts and the detection and the OCR, everything is handled internally within that.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no, sir, not internally, they have separate models for everything. If you look into the logs, so for that, they were using YOLO dock layout. You will see that under FFT, that, like, for everything, they have a separate model.
Krish NAik: It's not a single stage as well.
Murtuza Saifee: And we can configure it, which ones to use at which stage, right?
Krish NAik: They have all the options. It means that not, say, in their original SDK, they don't have the options so much.
Krish NAik: But I feel that the… at least the option that they provide, it's more than enough.
Krish NAik: Because the results that you will get with those models, because the original testing that the Shanghai AI Labs have done, they have only kept those models in the SDK. Other than that, some NVIDIA models and those models, they have not taken. Direct integration also, I don't think it is possible.
Krish NAik: Because, in their case, you know, if you look into the notebook, in every pipeline, they have separate models.
Krish NAik: Okay, in some cases, it can be CPU-based models if you're working only on a CPU-based environment, but they have, for every task, they have different models. It's not a single model who is doing the task.
Murtuza Saifee: So it's, like, pre-configured pipelines, so you just mentioned the pipeline.
Murtuza Saifee: Maybe the combination will be there.
Krish NAik: SDKs, it will be pre-configured. Like, JLM OCR, similarly, Paddle OCR, we are the… we are the new one there also. Most of the SDKs, because the research that they have done, they have only done the integration with the
Krish NAik: there is not a… till now, not a single implementation where you can actually do it. Then it will be a little bit custom, because you have to do more amount, and you have to look into… you have to separately download each model, load it into the memory, whereas in most of the SDKs, it's much optimized.
Krish NAik: via VLLM package, that I think.
Murtuza Saifee: So we'll be using most of the time these SDKs, like MinerU, Docklink, Grainite, these are all the SDK packages.
Krish NAik: like, IBM research is a standard.
Krish NAik: similarly, like, minor U, it has become a standard, okay, from Shanghai AI Labs and Open Data Lab. So, these are major, like, I feel that Open Data Lab has done a lot of good research. So, that's why I feel that they are widely used. And generally, this is the doc… only the ingestion pipeline, so you need GPU once.
Krish NAik: Only the indexing. Once it's done, rest for query time, you don't need a GPU source. Somehow, a cheaper solution, as compared to using Pulpan.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, and, so, in that docking green light example that we did, so, I didn't get one part, so, like, we enabled the layout parsing.
Murtuza Saifee: we have the table transformer, but we disabled the OCR. So, in that the OCR was not needed to capture anything, it was just done with…
Krish NAik: If you actually do an OCR, then it picks up the EV OCR and those ones. Those OCRs I didn't need. Here, actually, only two models will be used.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the model was… one was that, I think, some layout model was there, the dock layout. Okay.
Krish NAik: And the dock layout internally uses two different engines. One is the OCR engine of that, I think default configuration comes to easy OCR. Okay, and generally for scanned pages, it is used. Otherwise, for table detection, they use stable farmers.
Krish NAik: So, in that case, you really don't need to switch on the default one. The default one overwrites the implementation of your table formulas. That's why it's better to switch it on. That's why.
Murtuza Saifee: the documentary.
Krish NAik: Because that code snippet, exactly, I picked up from the documentation. Okay, just let me show, where from that I have taken it. Because, the doc link rewrite, docs, I think.
Krish NAik: So, it's written there, Docling granite talks.
Krish NAik: if you're working with her own-based models, I see her own models are much bigger, but yeah, ESC. So, this is the part where, that I've tested, and I think the last one was this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is output with this one. So I'm sharing this one, this is the actual Grenade talking documentation. From there, only I have taken this snippet.
Krish NAik: So you can have a look into the docs.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, okay, thanks. I think, the last thing probably is, I think Abhishek already raised this point, so probably we can discuss.
Krish NAik: Drop a mail and we connect.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, okay, thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, else, I'm sure the lung will raise that, but I cannot really hear you on.
Krish NAik: Anybody else want to raise their hands?
Krish NAik: All right, so I think, no answer is. So, guys, for today, I'll be concluding the session, but the notebook, the last one, the binary, your entire pipeline, please do the execution by yourself first.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's very, very important to go through the notebook, then you will understand that if you have equations, if you have everything that needs to be wrapped up. Okay, so that's why please go through that, how to handle images, everything is there. I've kept it, so do spend some time on that.
Krish NAik: Angshu, though you are raising your hand, like, you can let me know in the chat, Angshu.
Krish NAik: Thus, really, I cannot hear him. Santosh has released.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'll push.
Santosh Umargi: I sent you the mail, but it is failing, don't know why. It is saying…
Santosh Umargi: There was a problem delivering message,
Krish NAik: What is the email ID.
Santosh Umargi: Appaderkrishna.com, no?
Krish NAik: dot in.
Santosh Umargi: 13, okay.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, I will reshare that, but basically what happened, no, I have… I'm clearing the first rounds of most of the MNCs.
Santosh Umargi: But, like, in second round, no, they… the manager asking, like, scenario-based questions for the… this Jane AI, mislead rack systems and all, like…
Santosh Umargi: how the checking strategy, how to scale and all. So, I want, like, any, resource or, like, any single place is there, like, where I can refer those, because, right now, whatever projects I have shown, no, those are which we taken in our classes, no? That text to SQL and all.
Santosh Umargi: And in current… my experience, I'm just having the POC-type experience in my current organization.
Santosh Umargi: I'm coming from development background.
Krish NAik: Android.
Krish NAik: Scenario-based questions, see, like, I don't think there will be any resource, because it totally depends upon the project that you have written in your resume, or any POC or NVP that you might have mentioned.
Krish NAik: So, really, like, anybody… that is the tricky part where anybody can actually catch. Because in the scenario phase, really, like, anybody…
Krish NAik: Because it can be based on evaluation. Right now, I feel that most of the interviews, everybody's focusing much more on evaluation. But, again, like, your questions, like, you can let me know with respect to such questions, if anything can, I can respond back to you. Okay. Like, where you can connect us.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, yeah, I will drop you that mail. Actually, I have written all those questions which I got asked in the.
Krish NAik: Generally, right now, initially, three to four interviews can be like that, but slowly, slowly, you will understand that according to your project that you have mentioned in the resume, you know, what are the questions that are asked?
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, yeah, got it.
Krish NAik: Mataj, I'm not, like, really, I don't know, like, what is the profile he's doing separately.
Krish NAik: Alright, then.
Krish NAik: Sample ones, sample ones, really, like, I have asked few of them, neither of them responded. Let me see, like, one of them…
Krish NAik: a sample once, it means that it's a dependency from asking for someone's. Then I have to remove the personal information, then I have to show it to you.
Krish NAik: That's right.
Krish NAik: Let me see, I think Sunny has a few of them, but again, they are not from research prospect so much, little bit service-focused much.
Krish NAik: Let me get me a reminder, okay, even next week, then again, today I will connect with you guys, and then respond back to you on touch.
Krish NAik: All right, so I'll be concluding it. Okay, so let's, meet tomorrow, and we will continue a little bit about our project next year, so we'll start the project.
Krish NAik: No, excellent.
Krish NAik: Okay, all right. So, by the way, everyone, okay, so anyone says drop email. I was not active so much last week, but now I will be responding back to whoever is, just to meet.
Krish NAik: For a long time.
Krish NAik: Bye-bye, guys. Thank you, everyone, for joining.